<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">

<channel>
	<title>Christian Christiansen</title>
	<link>https://christianchristiansen.net/log/index.html</link>
	<description>Latest updates from Christian Christiansen's log.</description>

    <image>
	<url>https://christianchristiansen.net/favicon.ico</url>
	<title>Christian Christiansen</title>
	<link>https://christianchristiansen.net</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
    </image>
    <item>
        <title>25 songs and tracks of 2025</title>
        <link>https://christianchristiansen.net/log/25-songs-of-2025.html</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 20:32:17 AEDT</pubDate>
        <guid>
        https://christianchristiansen.net/log/25-songs-of-2025.html
        </guid>
        <description>
        
&lt;h1 class=&quot;title&quot;&gt;25 songs and tracks of 2025&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Little, if any, of 2025’s broader zeitgeist is reflected in the best
music of the year. &lt;i&gt;Facing War&lt;/i&gt;, a documentary following the trials and
tribulations of Jens Stoltenberg, the former Secretary General of NATO, shows a
world which is more split, strung between multiple possible nightmares, whilst
war and worse rage on. Possibly 2025’s best album of the year, &lt;i&gt;Big City Life&lt;/i&gt;
by Smerz, exists in a parallel reality. Catharina Stoltenberg (Jens’s daughter)
and Henriette Motzfeldt are two of the torch-bearers for a new sound coming
from between and beyond Nørrebro and Vesterbro. With bare outlines, these
twenty-and-thirty-year-olds allow our imaginations to roam unexplored terrains.
Straddling digital and urban worlds, we find nostalgia for a never time,
the allure of the dancefloor, and romance – as it ever was.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;outline-container-org33a84a1&quot; class=&quot;outline-2&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;org33a84a1&quot;&gt;25. Debbie Sings – Sunny Skies&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;outline-text-2&quot; id=&quot;text-org33a84a1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Power poptimists rejoice, with synths this obnoxious there’s no shame left to
lose. Embrace the crucifix of amps, emblaze your crop-top with a font tackier
than &lt;i&gt;brat&lt;/i&gt; and get down like it’s 2007 round Ed Banger’s. Debbie Sings, we
party.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;outline-container-org01d969a&quot; class=&quot;outline-2&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;org01d969a&quot;&gt;24. CHRIST DILLINGER – RIP HULK HOGAN&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;outline-text-2&quot; id=&quot;text-org01d969a&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Sincerity and satire have never been paired so beautifully together before.
Simultaneously grotesque, enthralling and hilarious, Christ Dillinger’s tribute
to self-professed racist and America’s greatest ever wrestler foregrounds
the ugly reality of who our entertainers are.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;outline-container-orga3da242&quot; class=&quot;outline-2&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;orga3da242&quot;&gt;23. Surgeon – Forgotten Gods&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;outline-text-2&quot; id=&quot;text-orga3da242&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
God knows a.m. or is it p.m.? All that matters is the beat, the next beat and
the space compressing and decompressing between. The right combination of
venue, crowd, sound system and track selection allows techno to work its magic
and enrapture its audience. With Forgotten Gods, Surgeon shows that he sure
knows all the conjuring tricks.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;outline-container-orgd057a8e&quot; class=&quot;outline-2&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;orgd057a8e&quot;&gt;22. Roberto Musci – Persistence of Vision&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;outline-text-2&quot; id=&quot;text-orgd057a8e&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The best contemplative pieces offer fertile soundscapes to plant new ideas and
watch them grow. Each listen may sprout vastly different shapes, but the
shadings of light and dark stay the same, providing set twists for thoughts to
navigate, as sounds move us from one space to another. Finely balanced, richly
rewarding.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;outline-container-org5075ef6&quot; class=&quot;outline-2&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;org5075ef6&quot;&gt;21. Moin – See (featuring Sophia Al-Maria &amp;amp; Ben Vince)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;outline-text-2&quot; id=&quot;text-org5075ef6&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Percussion, repetition, cycles of saxophone, spoken word, repeated, spoken
word, cycles of saxophone, contemplations, again, percussion, contemplate. See?
Percussion, repetition, cycles of saxophone, spoken word, repeated, spoken
word, cycles of saxophone, contemplations, again, percussion, contemplate. See.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;outline-container-org4d332b8&quot; class=&quot;outline-2&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;org4d332b8&quot;&gt;20. Avalon Emerson &amp;amp; the Charm – Eden&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;outline-text-2&quot; id=&quot;text-org4d332b8&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Breezy summers may evoke a certain care-freeness; what worries burden
sun-kissed faces? But long evenings allow old emotions to blow in, linger and
settle. Memories sharpen and resolutions to uphold past promises restore. For
Eden.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;outline-container-orgead529b&quot; class=&quot;outline-2&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;orgead529b&quot;&gt;19. Kathryn Mohr – Horizonless&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;outline-text-2&quot; id=&quot;text-orgead529b&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
It is dark outside already. Dusk is closing in on a dreary day, spent jogging
across wet leaves and wandering Viking graves. Clouds stretch past the
horizons, and beyond. There is a certain serenity to be enjoyed. Crackle of
rain, hiss of wind, the irrefutability of the season.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;outline-container-orga5a1487&quot; class=&quot;outline-2&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;orga5a1487&quot;&gt;18. Haloplus+ – Open Air Backseat&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;outline-text-2&quot; id=&quot;text-orga5a1487&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The liminal spaces in between our digital and non-digital realities remain
under-explored, though recently a couple of groups in and around Copenhagen
have set down a few poufs in the gaps between CPH and tucked–away Internet
snugs, grabbed a guitar and made themselves at home. These new Enos make Music
for Internet Airports –  and it’s bloody good.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;outline-container-orgab9fb0b&quot; class=&quot;outline-2&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;orgab9fb0b&quot;&gt;17. Oxis – Long Sardine&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;outline-text-2&quot; id=&quot;text-orgab9fb0b&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Oxis may claim there is something fishy at play here. But to the contrary.
Nostalgia is a simple longing for simpler times, evoked here by a simple ditty.
A fleeting wish, which slips away as quickly as it appeared.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;outline-container-orgf2e84c2&quot; class=&quot;outline-2&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;orgf2e84c2&quot;&gt;16. oqbqbo &amp;amp; Scandinavian Star – Sun Up&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;outline-text-2&quot; id=&quot;text-orgf2e84c2&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Terrifying infernos broiling with energy beam their light and brighten our
skies. During the long Scandinavian summer, the brilliance imbues positivity.
Sun Up, chin up – it’s all going to be alright.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;outline-container-org3cc95d3&quot; class=&quot;outline-2&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;org3cc95d3&quot;&gt;15. Joanne Robertson and Oliver Coates – Gown&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;outline-text-2&quot; id=&quot;text-org3cc95d3&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
From softly strum guitars, dulcet yet powerful strings and a voice which drifts
and glitters, Joanne Robertson weaves together the most invitingly hearty and
dazzling gown to curl up in and feel the waves of time crashing gently by.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;outline-container-org4741ee1&quot; class=&quot;outline-2&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;org4741ee1&quot;&gt;14. Vanessa Amara – Love won’t love you&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;outline-text-2&quot; id=&quot;text-org4741ee1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Each weekend, organs around the world sound to announce the arrival of the
bride and the impending nuptial union. Here, the organs sound a warning, or
perhaps they ruminate on the unidirectionality of love. It’s complicated,
either way.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;outline-container-org3cecca6&quot; class=&quot;outline-2&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;org3cecca6&quot;&gt;13. RIP Swirl – Let’s Make Out (featuring Ydegirl)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;outline-text-2&quot; id=&quot;text-org3cecca6&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The strains of desire can cripple a budding romantic’s heart by tearing their
inner world this way and that. In momentary swirling flashes though, the
tensions can align and all pull together in the same direction towards one
simple desire. Let’s Make Out is less an invitation, more a crying out for
resolution.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;outline-container-orgf652f7e&quot; class=&quot;outline-2&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;orgf652f7e&quot;&gt;12. Smerz – You got time and I got money - VVTZJ EDIT (featuring Clairo)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;outline-text-2&quot; id=&quot;text-orgf652f7e&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
An instant classic love song reimagined for the ballroom, to slow dance to
under flickering chandeliers. Clairo’s breathy vocals fill the air,
intertwining with the dreamy electric guitar and Smerz’s calm collected
delivery. The effect builds and builds, as powerful as any ballad, before
disappearing away behind thick veils into digital noise.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;outline-container-org40c12f4&quot; class=&quot;outline-2&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;org40c12f4&quot;&gt;11. Tyler, The Creator – Mommanem&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;outline-text-2&quot; id=&quot;text-org40c12f4&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Chest out, feet fleet, Tyler’s ready for a brawling. Run if you can. With Tyler
this livid, singing nursery rhymes about murder, you better pray it wasn’t you
who hurt his feelings. On his momma’nem.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;outline-container-org97b4b6b&quot; class=&quot;outline-2&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;org97b4b6b&quot;&gt;10. Hekt – Beautiful&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;outline-text-2&quot; id=&quot;text-org97b4b6b&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
With a surgeon’s precision, Hekt sculpts a banger. The drops’ smoothness belies
their ridicularity. Whether or not Hekt was grinning to himself whilst wielding
the scalpel is irrelevant, his artistry cannot be denied.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;outline-container-org35894ca&quot; class=&quot;outline-2&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;org35894ca&quot;&gt;9. Fine – Portal&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;outline-text-2&quot; id=&quot;text-org35894ca&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The art of subtlety is perhaps the one core commonality binding the Copenhagen
scene. Stripped back sketches hint at the opportunities beyond the void. Flicks
of melody call forth orchestral arrangements of Wagnerian proportions. But a
moment later, the daydream shifts, and we’re back in our bedrooms accompanied
only by our own thoughts.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;outline-container-orgf89af8f&quot; class=&quot;outline-2&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;orgf89af8f&quot;&gt;8. Elias Rønnenfelt – Mona Lisa&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;outline-text-2&quot; id=&quot;text-orgf89af8f&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
There is an undeniably Romantic edge to Rønnenfelt. Elements of another age,
when da Vinci was at large or Bataille wrote of eroticism – Rønnenfelt may
feel most at home ‘hanging ’neath the Sistine Chapel ceiling in the air’. But
it is his urgency to capture the moment which truly makes his music timeless.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;outline-container-orgd10aa67&quot; class=&quot;outline-2&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;orgd10aa67&quot;&gt;7. james K – Doom Bikini&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;outline-text-2&quot; id=&quot;text-orgd10aa67&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The strength of feeling which coarses through me when &lt;i&gt;Doom Bikini&lt;/i&gt; plays
easily outstrips my ability to coherently express the strength of those
feelings. james K has created a pop masterpiece with verses which glisten, even
better bridges which ratchet up the tension, and diabolical choruses. It is so
so so good.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;outline-container-org0f73fee&quot; class=&quot;outline-2&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;org0f73fee&quot;&gt;6. Soli City – Western Media&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;outline-text-2&quot; id=&quot;text-org0f73fee&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Little of world events has seaped through to the cultural soundscape of 2025. A
vanguard of Kneecap and Bob Vylan is not exactly quite like
&lt;i&gt;God Save The Queen&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;I Feel Love&lt;/i&gt;, or hell even whatever that first The X
Factor single was called, in capturing the sign of the times. Perhaps the
turbulence, speed and incomprehension of today is at fault. However, Soli
City’s clipped up musique concrète-ish piece shows how it is possible to still
strike a course through the noise.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;outline-container-orgd05f5f9&quot; class=&quot;outline-2&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;orgd05f5f9&quot;&gt;5. Anna B Savage – Talk To Me&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;outline-text-2&quot; id=&quot;text-orgd05f5f9&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
In music, 2025 was the year of love. &lt;i&gt;brat&lt;/i&gt; summer well and truly over, this
wasn’t love in the sense of hooking up, having a good time or loving labubus or
Limp Bizkit or whatever, it was inner peace and contentedness with those still
dear after post-after-party clarity. Seasides, snuggles, Sunday evening
Saturdays.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Love has rendered the dazzling acrobatics necessary to navigate the fault lines
in &lt;i&gt;in|FLUX&lt;/i&gt; superfluous. Anna B Savage’s virtuosic vocals have gained maturity
and tenderness. With lullabies gentle enough to lull a bull, this is the true
power of love.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;outline-container-orgf4b6319&quot; class=&quot;outline-2&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;orgf4b6319&quot;&gt;4. Dean Blunt &amp;amp; Elias Rønnenfelt – 7&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;outline-text-2&quot; id=&quot;text-orgf4b6319&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
It is cruel to tear &lt;i&gt;lucre&lt;/i&gt; apart into separate pieces. Indeed, the intial drop
as one continuous sixteen-minute track in addition to the perfunctory numeric
track names very much suggests that Blunt &amp;amp; co. intended &lt;i&gt;lucre&lt;/i&gt; to be
savoured whole.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
That being said, &lt;i&gt;7&lt;/i&gt;​’s moody optimism shines, whether stand-alone or as a coda.
Though &lt;i&gt;5&lt;/i&gt; may adorn Premier League footballers’ playlists, and &lt;i&gt;1&lt;/i&gt; breezes
past with Rønnenfelt’s languid &lt;i&gt;da&lt;/i&gt;​s, &lt;i&gt;lucre&lt;/i&gt;​’s heftiest piece, allowed the
space to flourish, best exhibits Blunt’s prowess as a producer and
Rønnenfelt’s ability to exude emotion from each syllable, vowel and utterance.
Longing strings, warm guitars, clean percussion and drawled vocals have struck
up a tune often enough – but never quite like this.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;outline-container-org9388519&quot; class=&quot;outline-2&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;org9388519&quot;&gt;3. james K – Play&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;outline-text-2&quot; id=&quot;text-org9388519&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I was loath to place the same artist twice upon this list, but allowed it in
the case of Rønnenfelt due to one of the tracks being a collaborative effort.
No such excuses for james K. Not even the excuse of different projects or
separate albums can save me. The strength of the music, however, can.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Trance as pop, breakdown as chorus, guitars as cool again, somehow.
&lt;i&gt;Friend&lt;/i&gt; is stellar throughout – and there exist valid claims for &lt;i&gt;Doom Bikini&lt;/i&gt;
to be the better song. But no other track of 2025 affirmed the importance and
poignancy of life as consistently for me.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;outline-container-orgb69775c&quot; class=&quot;outline-2&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;orgb69775c&quot;&gt;2. Shanti Celeste – Romance&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;outline-text-2&quot; id=&quot;text-orgb69775c&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Dive into the irisdescent bubble gum synths, frolick amongst the honey-dipped
vocals, bathe in the warmth of romance, baby, I won’t even be mad at being
adressed as baby. The lusciousness of the mid-range and the infectiousness of
the slightly off-kilter stabs of bass leave you craving for more and more.
House at its finest evokes an irresistible high. Paired with pop, the
temptations just grow.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;outline-container-org714df4d&quot; class=&quot;outline-2&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;org714df4d&quot;&gt;1. Smerz – You got time and I got money&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;outline-text-2&quot; id=&quot;text-org714df4d&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
You know it, I know it, any self-respecting music-lover knows it, Smerz have
fashioned a love song for the ages. The rest of the list is completely subject
to the whims of my opinion, but &lt;i&gt;You got time and I got money&lt;/i&gt; is hands down
the best song of the year. I was loath to give two entries to the same artist
or album, but &lt;i&gt;You got time and I got money&lt;/i&gt; easily merits its double
appearance, and potentially warrants an additional third – it is simply that
good.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Love can be disarmingly simple, as simple as ‘I like your shoes, I like
these clean t-shirts on you’. It might even render us incapable of formulating
correct sentences, see ‘I wanna talk much’, and dut-dut-du-ing arpeggios
instead. But there is nothing banal about love.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Three weeks ago my partner and I sat in a sauna with the good company of three
friends, staring out at an ink-black Limfjord. Ripples on the surface were
illuminated only by a lightbulb or two along a lonely pier. Our thoughts and
bodies oscillated between the heat of the sauna and the coldness of the water.
Bliss set in, nothing else could pierce the fierce tranquility we were wrapped
in. Nothing else could possibly matter. As when the keys kick in, the kick and
snare, and Catharina Stoltenberg’s voice washes over.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

        </description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <title>The White Book</title>
        <link>https://christianchristiansen.net/log/the-white-book.html</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 05:35:19 AEST</pubDate>
        <guid>
        https://christianchristiansen.net/log/the-white-book.html
        </guid>
        <description>
        
&lt;h1 class=&quot;title&quot;&gt;The White Book&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
New inventions require new terms. 电脑 (diànnăo in Mandarin), literally
electric brain, is the Chinese term for a computer. The Danes tried out
&lt;i&gt;datamat&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;arbejdsstation&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;edb-maskine&lt;/i&gt; before giving up and just copying
the English. The Koreans, with 컴퓨터 (keompyuteo), and Japanese, with
コンピュータ (konpyūta), did the same. Icelanders went with a bunch of
different terms, including loaning &lt;i&gt;computer&lt;/i&gt;, before settling on Sigurður
Nordal’s suggestion &lt;i&gt;tölva&lt;/i&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
This is represenative of Icelandic attempts to maintain an inner consistency to
their language. To a much lesser extent than most other European languages,
Icelandic has seen little change since the inital settlement of Iceland by the
Norse over a thousand years ago. Yes, the Runic alphabet was abandoned in
favour of a Latin-based one, words have been added and faded away from the
lexicon, and pronunications have drifted. Yet when compared to Iceland’s Norse
cousins on the European mainland, namely Norway, Sweden and Denmark, the drift
has been miniscule. The Scandinavians loaned words from their Hanseatic trading
partners and, due to Napoleon’s forays, even from the French. And though Old
English may be mutually intelligible to Icelanders even today, the English,
with their mongrel language, stand a snowball’s chance in hell in understanding
the tongue of those who roamed Old Blighty a millenium ago.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The unfortunate term for this phenonmeon is linguistic purity. Foreignness
immediately implies impurity, a tarnishing of what’s right, a sullying. I could
have sworn that I once watched a BBC documentary where some Icelandic scholars
were searching for an alternative term to ‘pure’ in order to discourage
unsavoury tourists (read: white supremacists) from visiting to enjoy an
‘unsullied’ culture. Alas, my bookmarks and Google-fu are failing me.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
‘White’, for me, evokes many similar feelings of discomfort. I still double
take whenever I read ‘The Whites’, a nickname for Leeds United (after the
colour of their Real Madrid inspired home kit), not a Mosley appreciation
group. Whities, too, which has thankfully since been renamed to AD 93, used to
cause me to squirm – a fantastic music label originally named after the
interplay of ‘YT’ (as the label originated as a Young Turks sub-label, which
itself has since been renamed to Young) with ‘white’ labels (which are records
without accompanying artwork, typically test presses, promos or bootlegs).
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;i&gt;The White Book&lt;/i&gt; by Han Kang, winner of the 2024 Nobel Prize in Literature,
translated by Deborah Smith, is suffused with whiteness. Snowflakes, blank
pages, too delicate flowers emerge from Kang’s prose turned poetry. The
sensitivity and preciseness and artfulness are a wonder to behold. Only first
half-way through, when an etymological discussion arises on ‘blank’ vs ‘blanc’,
can the text be accused of being bland.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
However, an uncomfortable emptiness pervades &lt;i&gt;The White Book&lt;/i&gt;. At first, it is
almost imperceptible, a slither missing. Yet as the words flow past, a chasm
emerges, where the words avoid mention. The chasm of grief. For here,
whiteness, above all, denotes not purity nor new beginnings, but the desolation
of a life lived around the contours of a life unlived. No words could describe
the sadness. Yet in &lt;i&gt;The White Book&lt;/i&gt;, Han Kang finds them.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;outline-container-org83adf00&quot; class=&quot;outline-2&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;org83adf00&quot;&gt;Appendix&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;outline-text-2&quot; id=&quot;text-org83adf00&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://thesquareball.net/leeds-united/the-whites-from-a-different-perspective/&quot;&gt;A fantastic article&lt;/a&gt; by Milan Khara which describes the experience of growing up
as a Leeds United fan during a time when there was ‘increasingly open racism on
display’.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Nic Tasker &lt;a href=&quot;https://ra.co/news/72819&quot;&gt;explains&lt;/a&gt; the change of name from Whities to AD 93.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
A personal favourite of mine of AD 93’s output is Whities 006 by Avalon
Emerson, perhaps the best DJ I have ever seen perform.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
My copy of the The White Book was gifted to me by Georgie and Dan. Thank you.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

        </description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <title>Northern Winter Beat 2025</title>
        <link>https://christianchristiansen.net/log/northern-winter-beat-2025.html</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2025 19:24:58 AEDT</pubDate>
        <guid>
        https://christianchristiansen.net/log/northern-winter-beat-2025.html
        </guid>
        <description>

&lt;h1 class=&quot;title&quot;&gt;Northern Winter Beat 2025&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
For three evenings in February, Aalborg plays host to Northern Winter Beat, a
music festival set to defrost and challenge its audience.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;outline-container-org78a2e9d&quot; class=&quot;outline-2&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;org78a2e9d&quot;&gt;Thursday&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;outline-text-2&quot; id=&quot;text-org78a2e9d&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The 2025 edition began with a performance from &lt;b&gt;Lubomyr Melnyk&lt;/b&gt;, a Ukrainian
pianist, at Budolfi Church, Aalborg’s grandest building. Over six centuries
worth of architecture and extravagant decoration set the stage to be graced by
a scruffy Melnyk, who lamented the advent of plastic listening devices,
extolled the virtues of listening live or on wooden speakers, and, ‘Maybe the
hippies were right. I’m not a hippy, at least no longer. Even though… I just
don’t have time to deal with my beard or – Oh no, I was supposed to have
brushed my hair,’ he tailed away before offering us a beautiful mandala. His
notes painted the finest Monet, each key press a ripple in a lily pond, a
reflection of the mangroves above, as numerous as raindrops in a passing
shower, each as delicate as a leaf’s rustle. His hands danced with impossible
technique. Debussy and Gould sprung to mind, but this was truly a maximalist’s
vision of Glass, Reich and Riley. What have the minimalists wrought? A warning
of the evils of Spotify preceded his following piece, Butterfly, where he
played a duet with a recording of himself. If the mandala acted as a testament
to his technicality, Butterfly confirmed his intense musicality. Melodies
sprung from the shifting harmonic undergrowth, as radiant as new blooming
petals, before wilting away into the high ceilings and crypts below. Third and
finally, Melnyk introduced a piece to acknowledge the bravery of Ukrainians. He
spoke on Putin and Putin’s hate of Ukrainians, for ‘they are the only ones who
can truly see the darkness of the Russian’s soul.’ The piece began with a ghost
haunting the speakers. Mid-range feedback howled persistently, fading away only
to return.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
A stone throw’s away at Studenterhuset Café, &lt;b&gt;Lars Bech Pilgaard&lt;/b&gt; took a violin
bow to a guitar, and with it dared us to leave. Plenty did. His second piece
exhibited more recognisable forms of technique, demonstrating an evident
talent, which was gleefully wielded in pursuit of novelty instead of, say,
harmony or melody or rhythm. ‘Imagine a bagpipe – or don’t,’ he suggested prior
to a piece which was more reminiscent of Lightning Bolt without the drums.
Whilst picking up a banjo for his next piece, he attempted to advertise his
wares, before realising his folly. As he played, he mumbled and grumbled,
completely enraptured by the soundscape he concocted, animated with eyes closed
by the interplay of string against string, his body wracked around his
instrument. At the end, he thanked us for sticking it out with him. I bought a
record.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Another soloist closed out the Thursday at Studenterhuset Hall. &lt;b&gt;Zola Jesus&lt;/b&gt;
played a grand piano which inexplicably had its top faced towards the back of
the stage instead of the audience. Following Pilgaard, the mere presence of
song and structure seemed shocking. Her voice was the real star, the piano
acted simply as a placeholder for an imagined orchestra. Jesus, too, was
wrapped up in her own world, though on occasion she would remember the
crowd, and engage with us with almost comical zeal. But the microphone was
too close and the piano chords too plain. Thursday night’s a school night;
we left early.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;outline-container-org1cbc0a3&quot; class=&quot;outline-2&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;org1cbc0a3&quot;&gt;Friday&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;outline-text-2&quot; id=&quot;text-org1cbc0a3&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Utzon Center, the final building to be realised by Jørn Utzon, famed architect
of the Sydney Opera House, sits on the bank of the Limfjord, its
characteristically wave-like ceilings greet the passing sound. &lt;b&gt;Virta&lt;/b&gt;, a trio
of drummer, guitarist and trumpeter/digital miscellaneaist/wailing Finn, took
to the stage, the windows behind providing a panorama of the Limfjord and
Nørresundby. The three of them sculpted sound which expanded gradually as
interlocking crescendos coalesced, iridescent streaks emerged as the air grew
thicker. The drummer was blatantly very good. So good I wished to see the band
sabotage their own rhythms, yet the operation remained slick. A smiley lead
thanked us profusely between each song. A good start to the Friday schedule,
they proved to be the highlight of the day.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Naima Bock&lt;/b&gt; and an accompanying quartet were already well under way by the
time we had hurried to Vor Frelsers church. The candle-lit and warm interior, a
stark contrast to the winter conditions outside, lulled us. The music, too,
comforted like soup. Only a couple of false starts roused us from our drowsy
state. Bock mentioned that she had chosen more subdued songs, to match the
setting. Funny, given that the last musical act we’d seen perform here was
Swans.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Headline act Diana Barkot of Pussy Riot performed next, but I took a chance on
&lt;b&gt;Snapped Ankles&lt;/b&gt; instead. A certain lairiness was purring through the room at
Huset when I arrived, the nordjysk crowd itching for a good time. The synth
beat provided cover for nods around the room, signalling intent. A trio of
London lads dressed head-to-toe in camourflage gone silly sensed the hype and
took to the mic. Alas, the drum machine never kicked in, the amp having caught
flu on the flight over, according to the lead lad. ‘Fuck Spotify, for giving
the amp flu,’ he then proclaimed, stroking his camo beard, whilst tech lad
troubleshooted and lad-in-waiting giggled, ‘It can’t get any worse.’ The crowd
trickled out and searched elsewhere, as each stop-start deflated our hopes of a
party ever kicking off.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I still wanted to see Diana Burkot, and was excited to see her perform with
&lt;b&gt;New Age Doom&lt;/b&gt;, based off of my cursory pre-festival research. (According to my
spies, Diana Burkot​’s solo show delivered a powerful message, however, what
the message was remained unclear.) A solitary Greg Valou appeared at
Studenterhuset Hall, apologised for a lack of a drummer, announced a set of
mostly drone music with a sprinkling of field recordings and vocal tracks. No
Pussy Riot in sight. Valou, too, took a violin bow to his guitar, but his use
was less an exploration of form than Pilgaard, more an application of technique
to layer texture upon more texture, blanketting us with excessive tog. With no
rhythm or rhyme to mark undulations in time, a monotone set in. Though the
field recordings added splashes of colour and Scratch’s voice will live
forever, neither could stave off the disappointment of expectations left
unfulfilled. (In contrast, my partner, who went to see Buzz’ Ayaz instead, was
bouncing from the walls with band tee and record in hand when she got home.)
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;outline-container-org5d2c69e&quot; class=&quot;outline-2&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;org5d2c69e&quot;&gt;Saturday&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;outline-text-2&quot; id=&quot;text-org5d2c69e&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Gråbrødrekloster Museet has one of the coolest entrances to a museum. Its
doorway hides in plain sight in the heart of Aalborg, right in front of
Salling, the city’s busiest department store. Few notice the grey-robed monks
adorning the standalone lift to the skeletons below. Forty-five minutes prior
to a gig capped at 35, a gaggle of us were handed yellow tickets with
instructions to meet later. When the time came, a man summoned us, took us
through another entrance, offered us a shot of dubious liquor and we
entered to see &lt;b&gt;Elias Rønnenfelt&lt;/b&gt; bundled around his guitar. With
characteristic nonchalance he threw himself into song, and against the glass
panes guarding the museum’s treasures, setting off the alarms outside. His
acoustic set included some Iceage tracks, a brilliant rendition of Calenture
from his Marching Church project, plus a couple of requests at the end.
Stripped to just himself and a guitar, Rønnenfelt’s talent for guitar-playing
came to the fore, his songwriting already undeniable. I would have gladly
listened to his entire discography (lucre, Vår, To The Comrades/Jackie,
Dragged, even the atrocious Silent Night karaoke) multiple times repeated,
however after 30 minutes it was all over. He invited us to join him later.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
At Huset, &lt;b&gt;Fitnesss&lt;/b&gt; terrorised us. Time, sound, space, light and mind became
fluid. It was some neo-fucking-pagan shit. Words are inadequate. Awe-inducing.
I left early.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Elias Rønnenfelt&lt;/b&gt; was on stage again, this time at Utzon Center flanked by a
bassist and a drummer, stand-ins for Lola Hammerich of Baby In Vain (see last
year’s &lt;a href=&quot;./northern-winter-beat-2024.html&quot;&gt;review&lt;/a&gt;) and Tobias Laust. With the backing of a band, the songs were
more fully realised than his solo set earlier. Heavy Glory and lucre featured
heavily this time, with a short foray into Throughout The Borders. The
collaborations with Dean Blunt sounded tantalisingly short; fragile songs like
Soldier Song were carried by Rønnenfelt’s magnetism; Sound of Confusion proved
that even without Iceage, Rønnenfelt can brew up a hell of a storm. A man old
enough to know better started swaying and propped himself against the stand
holding up a speaker, his festivities having already got the better of him,
taking all those within his vicinity out of the moment, as the fear of timber
loomed large. After too long a while, the drunk took himself away, and we were
able to enjoy a beautiful solo rendition of Against The Moon, undisturbed by
one of Pieter Bruegel’s bacchanalists.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Mermaid Chunky&lt;/b&gt; were in full swing by the time we arrived at Huset. The
A-level art project gone overboard consisted of a duo in ridiculous outfits
singing ridiculous songs in front of a visual art projection which may have
been a video but I suspect to be an over-elaborate gigabyte-sized PowerPoint
presentation. 2k era aesthetics gone 4k – roll over Superorganism, this is the
sound of the Internet. When drip drip drop Mermaid Chunky broke into Little
April Shower, my partner went wild. The crowd danced and pranced. Near the end,
Mermaid Chunky asked giddily, ‘Can we get some dry ice in here please? The
previous act was crazy, you couldn’t see anything. It was mad, there was a man
crawling on the floor. We’ll pay.’
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Eleven performances deep, we reconvened at Studenterhuset Café for the last
act. Our spies reported back that Kanaan were good and Dungen too, and bemoaned
various bodily ailments. A four-armed blunt-smoking-frog-caped
rat-god-worshipper rushed on stage, told us all that Northern Europeans are
perceived as cold in Colombia (to which an audience member replied, ‘we are!’)
and then said how that we were actually all really rather nice. &lt;b&gt;Julián
Mayorga&lt;/b&gt; then began a tale about a dog which had been left rotting on the
roadside, and how Jesus – this is a true story – walked past, disgusted and
confused by it, and the experience of all of this from the perspective of the
dead dog, in the form of song. Fun ensued, sore backs be damned. Chak chak chak
chak confetti!
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

        </description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <title>De rerum natura</title>
        <link>https://christianchristiansen.net/log/de-rerum-natura.html</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 07:39:11 AEDT</pubDate>
        <guid>
        https://christianchristiansen.net/log/de-rerum-natura.html
        </guid>
        <description>

&lt;h1 class=&quot;title&quot;&gt;De rerum natura&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
As his first act as the prime minister of Canada, Mark Carney, voted in as the
leader of the Liberal Party, has signed away consumer carbon tax. Six years
prior, in 2019, he was a UN Special Envoy for Climate Change. In 2021, he
launched the Glasgow Financial Alliance for Net Zero. In March 2021, in an
interview on CBC’s Rosemary Burton Live, he said,
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
There’s a recognition that the advice of scientists should be listened to. They
advised on the risks of pandemics and we didn’t fully listen to them anywhere
in the world. They’ve been advising for a long time of the risks on climate
change. It is time to listen.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
And instead, to repeat, his first act once he became prime minister, within
hours of his swearing in ceremony, was to repeal consumer carbon tax. What
gives?
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
In the last Australian federal election, held on the 21st May 2022, the
incumbent Liberals, headed by Scott Morrison, and their coalition partners the
Nationals, took a beating. Many voters defected to Labor, which won a majority
of seats, the first majority since 2007. Others, especially in the Liberal
heartlands of Australian suburbia, defected to a loose grouping of so-called
teal independents; the colour teal supposedly invoking their blue (i.e.
conservative) politics mixed in with a sprinkling of green.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Given the timing, the federal government’s handling of COVID-19 was, of course,
on the ballot paper. However, much of the Australian response to COVID-19 was
covered by state governments, not federal. The true issue at hand was Scott
Morrison – in particular his shambolic lack of leadership during Black Summer
and the ensuing floods. Morrison’s behaviour was hardly surprising, given
that in 2017 he brought a lump of coal to parliament to instigate a
self-induced show-and-tell, ‘This is coal. Don’t be afraid. Don’t be scared. It
won’t hurt you.’ Yet when the worst fires Australia has ever seen raged,
Morrison was found hiding in Hawaii.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
A month prior to the election, on the 9th April 2022, I partook in Salvage, a
community arts project held in Lithgow, a town in New South Wales circa 150 km
west of Sydney. Audience and performers gathered together to come to terms with
the fire, to grieve. Many had fought to save their property, to help
neighbours, to support those most desperately in need; all had witnessed the
devastation. A circle of women recreated their knitting of clothes for burnt
koalas and other critters of the bush; recordings of local community members
recalled their experiences during the aftermath; a huge burnt log lay in the
middle of the town hall, nature’s charred carcass the focus of it all. No
photos, videos or visual representations of fire were present. Songs were sung,
poems were recited, flyers for a missing person were distributed, a photo of
Scott Morrison bedecked in Hawaiian tourist attire grinning smugly from the
strips of paper.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I had first bumped into one of Salvage’s organisers, Sue, around Christmas time
in 2019 on a train in the UK. My partner and I expressed our reservations about
our imminent move to Australia, given the then hellish conditions. Sue
proceeded to show us hour-old photos of mushroom clouds, which did little to
avail us of our worries. Once in Sydney, we waded through flooded streets, and
in early 2020, Sue, together with James, another Salvage organiser, took us out
to near Lithgow to see the black cliff faces, the landscape scorched as far as
the eye could see. Later, I worked for a software company which provided
mapping services for fire agencies in Australia. We were told to refrain from
using any photos of Black Summer, due to the deep trauma of those months. Five
Christmases after that chance train encounter, my partner gifted me Highway to
Hell by Joëlle Gergis.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Highway to Hell is the 94th issue of Quarterly Essay, an Australian publication
with not only a self-explanatory name, but also sufficient heft to affect
the Australian national discourse. In Highway to Hell, Joëlle Gergis, a climate
scientist and lead author of the Intergovernmental Panel of Climate Change’s
(IPCC) Sixth Assessment Report, laments the willful ignorance of the Australian
elite and public to the problem of climate change. Fact after fact is dispensed
to bolster the reality too dire to confront. Even with the change in
government, too many simply fluctuate between outright denial and sticking
their heads in the sand. In 2024, Anthony Albanese, leader of the incumbent
Labor party, chose to expand four coal mines. However, once flames start
sucking the oxygen from our lungs, both denial and wishful thinking become less
tenable coping strategies.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
In 2016, fires surrounded Fort McMurray, the heart of Canada’s bitumen
industry. In a press conference held on the 3rd May at 11:00 am, Darby Allen,
the municipal fire chief, said, ‘People need to go to work: Mum needs to take
the kids to school, Dad takes the guys to the ballgame afterwards – but just be
cognisant that this is a serious situation.’ By 6:49 pm, much of Fort McMurray
was on fire and there were evacuation orders for the entire town. By the
evening, an interview with the CBC showed Allen as a changed man.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I – I would say it’s been the – it’s been the worst day of my career. And I am
uh – you know, the whole uh – the people here are devastated. Everyone’s
devastated. The community is gonna be devastated. This is going to go on; this
is gonna take us a while to come back from, but we – we’ll come back.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
We’ve had a devastatin’ day. Um – Fort McMurray has been overrun by wildfire.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Fire Weather by John Vaillant published in 2023 gives a blow-by-blow account of
what came to be known as The Beast. (I thank Rob, a family friend, for the
book recommendation.) Fire Weather constitutes three parts, Origin Stories,
Fire Weather and Reckoning. The first part introduces the reader to the
vistas and history of Alberta, and how bitumen, a tar-like substance which
after much wrangling can potentially be turned into a usable fuel, came to be
extracted, creating Mordor-like scars in the Earth north of Fort McMurray.
The second part covers the fire: the shock, the incomprehension, the bravery,
the fear. There are no prizes for correctly guessing what Reckoning is about.
By repeatedly prefacing the Fort McMurray fire with humans’ capacity to destroy
their habitats and ability to remain oblivious to imminent ruin, by the time
Vaillant tells the story of 2016, readers are prepared for the inevitable. Yet
the ferocity of the phenomenon still astounds. Even after Vaillant invokes the
Lucretius problem, first coined by Nassim Nicholas Taleb – namely that a little
river may seem to one, who has never seen a larger, the greatest – it remains
difficult to grasp the scale. But the repeated examples are effective,
especially when coupled with more simple thought experiments, reduced to more
manageable sizes. (Particularly graphic was the idea of a Chevy Silverado’s
tail pipe being directed right back into the vehicle, which would kill the
driver and all passengers within minutes. Directed into the driver’s living
room, all would be dead within the hour.) The repeated foreshadowing followed
by the horror means that by the time Reckoning comes around, it is impossible
to downplay the severity of our lot. In late September 2015, seven months
prior to the Fort McMurray Fire, then the governor of the Bank of England, the
Albertan Mark Carney said, ‘The challenges currently posed by climate change
pale in significance compared with what might come… Once climate change becomes
a defining issue for financial stability, it may already be too late.’
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
‘How can we scientists get the message effectively across?’ seems to be the
primary question which haunts Joëlle Gergis. With Fire Weather, John Vaillant
shows a possible way. And to those who still refuse to listen, we must say, we
have to embrace reality to change it effectively. To do otherwise is either
cowardly or foolish.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
C’est fous. C’est simple. C’est fous. Point final.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Mark Carney, it may be wise to listen to your own words. You may learn
something.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;outline-container-org1c89ec2&quot; class=&quot;outline-2&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;org1c89ec2&quot;&gt;Appendix&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;outline-text-2&quot; id=&quot;text-org1c89ec2&quot;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;outline-container-org9ef9460&quot; class=&quot;outline-3&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;org9ef9460&quot;&gt;The Lucretius problem&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;outline-text-3&quot; id=&quot;text-org9ef9460&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The original Latin from which the Lucretius problem gains its name, is as
follows:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
scilicet et fluvius qui visus maximus ei, &lt;br /&gt;
qui non ante aliquem maiorem vidit, et ingens &lt;br /&gt;
arbor homoque videtur et omnia de genere omni &lt;br /&gt;
maxima quae vidit quisque, haec ingentia fingit, &lt;br /&gt;
cum tamen omnia cum caelo terraque marique &lt;br /&gt;
nil sint ad summam summai totius omnem.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;quoter&quot;&gt;Lucretius, De rerum natura, liber sextus&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Nassim Nicholas Taleb’s translation in Antifragile, ‘the fool believes that the
tallest mountain in the world will be equal to the tallest one he has
observed’, strikes me to be rather loose, given that in this snippet Lucretius
mentions neither fools nor mountains.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;outline-container-org32541ae&quot; class=&quot;outline-3&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;org32541ae&quot;&gt;Mark Carney’s September 2015 speech&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;outline-text-3&quot; id=&quot;text-org32541ae&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bankofengland.co.uk/-/media/boe/files/speech/2015/breaking-the-tragedy-of-the-horizon-climate-change-and-financial-stability.pdf&quot;&gt;text&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=V5c-eqNxeSQ&quot;&gt;full video&lt;/a&gt; of the speech can be found on the
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bankofengland.co.uk/speech/2015/breaking-the-tragedy-of-the-horizon-climate-change-and-financial-stability&quot;&gt;Bank of England’s website&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;outline-container-org3b78ba2&quot; class=&quot;outline-3&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;org3b78ba2&quot;&gt;Scars of the bitumen industry&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;outline-text-3&quot; id=&quot;text-org3b78ba2&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://firms.modaps.eosdis.nasa.gov/map/#d:today;@-111.41,57.09,9.72z&quot;&gt;Zoom in and out to see the full extent&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;outline-container-org9daed64&quot; class=&quot;outline-3&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;org9daed64&quot;&gt;Darby Allen’s morning press conference&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;outline-text-3&quot; id=&quot;text-org9daed64&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=55O3jp8thKM&amp;amp;t=1469s&quot;&gt;fire update&lt;/a&gt; can be found on YouTube.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;outline-container-orgf6ed62e&quot; class=&quot;outline-3&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;orgf6ed62e&quot;&gt;Darby Allen’s evening interview with CBC&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;outline-text-3&quot; id=&quot;text-orgf6ed62e&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ovM0uT_D5Z4&quot;&gt;interview&lt;/a&gt; can be found on YouTube.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;outline-container-orga36fff2&quot; class=&quot;outline-3&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;orga36fff2&quot;&gt;Footage of the Fort McMurray fire&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;outline-text-3&quot; id=&quot;text-orga36fff2&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
It has to be seen to be believed. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7E_OLgC4nV0&quot;&gt;This will increasingly become our new reality.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

        </description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <title>Trip to a wedding</title>
        <link>https://christianchristiansen.net/log/trip-to-a-wedding.html</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2024 05:49:20 AEDT</pubDate>
        <guid>
        https://christianchristiansen.net/log/trip-to-a-wedding.html
        </guid>
        <description>

&lt;h1 class=&quot;title&quot;&gt;Trip to a wedding&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
In a rush after Danish class, I grabbed a luggage case, one of my partner’s, I
had no time to fish out my own, I’m not sure where it’s stored anyway, I hoped
she would be okay with it, if not…
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Anyway, where was I? I get confused. I grabbed a luggage case. Passport, yes,
as always in the inside pocket, and,
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
This detail is going to be tedious, isn’t it? It reads far too much like a
contemporary novel but one that is on the tail-end of whatever contemporary
this current contemporary is.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
So I got to the airport with plenty of time. Aalborg airport is shiny, small
and most importantly, not busy. No queues, no trouble. One vegan option was
available and I bought Der Spiegel to bide the time. I’d never read Der Spiegel
before and I was pleasantly surprised. I still haven’t kicked the tone, it’s
too conversational, it’s too easy. No friction or tension exists. Plain crisps
– no thanks. Even then though, plain crisps are better than this. Damp plain
crisps. That’s more like it.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I guess some tension could exist in the story from now, as I was sat on the
plane without a long transfer time at Schiphol, but the plane was yet to move.
A previous taxi driver had forewarned of delays from/to Amsterdam, or was it
cancellations? I’m unsure what he was trying to convey anyway. Chatter to a
passenger, wind to the night.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
But the tension doesn’t really work, because I know I made it. My luggage
didn’t (well, it does eventually), but I did. And even without the luggage, I
had already hatched a plan, buy a shirt and socks, potentially shoes, which the
man at M&amp;amp;S later talks me into, some rip-off Dr. Martens for £60 I hope to get
back from KLM after I’ve finished writing this up. Maybe that’s the tension,
will I get the money back or not? I don’t know. The total comes to £123.35, so
I guess the stakes aren’t too high – ah well.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
At passport control I spotted a bunch of bright red passports. I’d already
heard a Germanic language which wasn’t Dutch or German as I knew then, and then
I saw the cross. The Swiss. Thursday, Europa League. A hand touched my
shoulder. Glen! The best man. Yes. I waited for him at the conveyor belt,
whilst a young dog was let off the lead by a police officer. The dog jumped
over each bag, wagged its tail ferociously, squatted down, and started pissing
on the sliding black rubber panels. The piss travelled along and sloshed around
the corner. ‘She’s still a puppy,’ the copper explained. ‘And gets too
excited,’ she added. I then went for a wee myself. Too excited too, evidently.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Is there anything new I can say about lost luggage? Or Premier Inn? Grand
Central in Belfast is new, but is there anything new about it apart from its
existence?
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Weddings are weddings. Personal. It’s good to see old faces, to catch-up, to
see variations of your friend in old, young and other sex forms. The ceremony,
the children, the speeches, the children, the food, the children, the dancing,
are there even more children?
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Is there anything else I want to add? Der Spiegel is surprisingly good. I
already said that. At least as good as crisps.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Ah yes, one last bit, on connections again. The journey back included an hour
to transfer, so no intrigue there. However, I wasn’t assigned a seat number for
the second leg; I was on the waiting list. The man behind the desk at Belfast
deferred me to the staff at the gate in Schiphol. I got to the gate.
‘Christiansen?’ she asked. ‘Yes, that’s me,‘ I replied. She scanned
my boarding pass. ‘No sir. You’re Aalborg. Don’t get confused,’ she added. I
looked up at the screen. Kristiansand.
&lt;/p&gt;

        </description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <title>Cultural stagnation: what’s so important about culture?</title>
        <link>https://christianchristiansen.net/log/cultural-stagnation-whats-so-important-about-culture.html</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2024 04:33:12 AEDT</pubDate>
        <guid>
        https://christianchristiansen.net/log/cultural-stagnation-whats-so-important-about-culture.html
        </guid>
        <description>

&lt;h1 class=&quot;title&quot;&gt;Cultural stagnation: what’s so important about culture?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Exercise left for the reader.
&lt;/p&gt;

        </description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <title>Cultural stagnation: false start</title>
        <link>https://christianchristiansen.net/log/cultural-stagnation-false-start.html</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2024 17:27:28 AEST</pubDate>
        <guid>
        https://christianchristiansen.net/log/cultural-stagnation-false-start.html
        </guid>
        <description>

&lt;h1 class=&quot;title&quot;&gt;Cultural stagnation: false start&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
What are the most salient reasons for cultural stagnation? I wish to write an
essay which addresses this. Yet each attempt so far has failed to unburden
itself from the weight of the necessary preamble. Before seeking explanations
for a phenomenon, the phenomenon’s existence should ideally first be
established. Other people’s insistence on the phenomenon does not suffice. (For
the sake of even more thoroughness, before one even embarks on proving the
phenomenon’s existence, one should first argue why the phenomenon at hand is
worthy of discussion.)
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Establishing that cultural stagnation is happening is a fool’s errand. Culture
is vast, amorphous, multi-dimensional and intangible aside from the artefacts
left in its wake. A measure of culture would have to collate, sort and order
these artefacts ­ jeans, playlists, reaction videos, fan fiction ­ and extract
quantitative data from them in a manner which looks about right to the naked
eye, and would yet still suffer from all of the shortcomings of large societal
measures such as GDP. Even if a measure was to show a slowdown in cultural
change, the methodology would have to be dissected. What localities and media
were included? If there is a cultural slowdown in Brooklyn, is that offset by a
boon in Zanzibar? And if rock is dead (or dying or undead), is that because
podcasts are alive? (To use a historical case: though opera zombified after
Wagner, there is no sane claim for a lack of innovation in Western music in the
20th century.)
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Should the measures still hold and we can confidently say that yes, on the
whole, culture has stagnated, we would then have to wrangle with the implied
aesthetic judgement inherent in the term &lt;i&gt;stagnation&lt;/i&gt;. Stagnation is bad, but
is the slowdown of cultural change a necessarily bad thing? Have not previous
periods of cultural stability led to fantastic pieces of art? Must every
decade be as culturally disruptive as the 1960s? Surely some of David Bowie’s
forays (take The Laughing Gnome for example or a good chunk of his works in the
1990s) showcase that there is nothing inherently good with innovation. Some
cultural terrain may be best left undisturbed. Yet even now, though the topic
of whether cultural innovation/stability is good/bad is definitely worthy of
further discussion, we have yet to reach the true question I seek to tackle:
why cultural stagnation? (And potentially, wherefore cultural innovation?)
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
So long as people have compared contemporary art to those of yester years, the
topic of cultural stagnation has never strayed far. Any essay seeking to shine
new light on the topic would first have to acknowledge prior work done,
take stock of each explanation, travel further down roads already mapped out
where required, before striking into the wilderness and forging new paths. And
only now would the fun begin.
&lt;/p&gt;

        </description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <title>Northern Winter Beat 2024</title>
        <link>https://christianchristiansen.net/log/northern-winter-beat-2024.html</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2024 21:59:15 AEDT</pubDate>
        <guid>
        https://christianchristiansen.net/log/northern-winter-beat-2024.html
        </guid>
        <description>

&lt;h1 class=&quot;title&quot;&gt;Northern Winter Beat 2024&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
In the depths of each February, Aalborg, a city split by a fjord, hosts
Northern Winter Beat, a music festival of odd-ball bands and askew soloists. I
saw six acts in the 2024 edition, across two days in five different rooms at
three different locations.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Six performers took to the stage when I saw &lt;b&gt;HHY &amp;amp; The Macumbas&lt;/b&gt; on the Friday:
two drummers, two synth tweakers, a trumpet, and a shaking man with his body
turned away from us and an orange mask covering the back of his head. He
throbbed and jiggled, shook and wiggled, his mask’s nose constantly jeered at
us, its warning orange gleaming along with one of the synth tweakers’ cyan
trousers. Little of the man’s jiggling coincided with his bandmates’s
movements, but not many of their movements coincided with one another either.
Due to the lack of cohesion in dance, nodding – and fashion – I soon zoned in
on the interplay between the two drummers. Rhythms bounced and sparked off one
another, before shifting and rearing their heads unexpectedly elsewhere. The
feints and switches challenged our bodies to lock in and grab hold of any
semblance of a beat, to drink deeply from the space being gradually smothered
between the two drums.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
When he was head coach at Leeds United, the ever humble Marcelo Bielsa resisted
the assertion that he had somehow improved his charges’s footballing abilities;
he had merely helped them realise the potential which had already existed
within themselves. As I danced, I wondered whether that’s what music does. Does
music help us realise our bodies’ potential for movement and our psyches’
potential for emotion? Like Michelangelo’s quarried stone, we are already the
masterpiece within, we just require a maestro to help unleash us. In that case,
the two drummers in front of me were unlocking new twists and turns from within
me through their novel compressions and elongations of time. But this is
evidently horseshit. We are not masterpieces within quarried stone. Marcelo
Bielsa &lt;i&gt;did&lt;/i&gt; improve his players. And I, and the rest of the audience, was
shaking and wiggling just like the masked man, out of sync with everybody else,
lost to our own rhythms.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Julie Byrne&lt;/b&gt; was next. She was accompanied by a harpist and a violinist, a
violinist cloaked by earnestness and solemnity. Each song was performed
sincerely, with an undeniably beautiful voice, though the voice always stayed
within, curled up with its comfort blanket. Each song’s lyrics wafted over me.
I believe mountains and nature were mentioned, but their might and scale were
never evoked. The instrumental backing was mostly sufficient, but never more. I
wondered of the harpist if this was the future she had imagined for herself
when she spent countless hours mastering her control and technique, to be
plucking out simple arpeggios to sound pretty in the background.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I arrived late to the next act. I was waiting in the main room until I
overheard that the duo were already playing in the second room. I didn’t know
that there was a second room. But if there ever was a band made for unknown
second rooms, &lt;b&gt;Cantenac Dagar&lt;/b&gt; are it. After walking through hanging beads, I
shuffled along in the dark to find a spot to stand in the circle surrounding
a banjo-player and a beatboxer with an itchy throat. Banjo torturer and beat
conjurer may be more accurate descriptions. A violin bow screeched against
banjo strings; mouth beats mixed with coughs and jangling chains. As the
screeches droned and the beats ebbed and flowed and midnight drew near and I
looked around at the couple dozen of us gathered in a circle in a dark attic
room with the iciness of a Northern winter outside, I had come the closest to
partaking in a pagan ritual I had ever come, I thought. A pagan ritual to
summon a god. Not a major god – the music wasn’t intense enough. Maybe the god
of strepsils.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Saturday proved more fruitful, with performances from Baby in Vain, Föllakzoid
and Chris Imler.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
A steady pulse set the stage for &lt;b&gt;Föllakzoid&lt;/b&gt;. The beat gradually morphed,
adding an additional hit here, stripping back to the barebones there. Years of
early mornings in Offenbach kicked in as I focussed in on the miniscule and
rode the scintillating crunch of the hi-hat. A real hi-hat, for there was a
real drummer on stage on the right flank, an electronics twiggler on the left,
and up front – and what a frontwoman – was Domingæ. She played with the light,
and us, blinding members of the crowd with reflections of stage bulbs bouncing
of the shine of the scratchpad of her guitar. She seduced and stripped, urging
us to embrace her music and sexuality. But we were the ones being watched,
being judged, being dared by Domingæ. Were we audience enough for her?
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The next act, &lt;b&gt;Chris Imler&lt;/b&gt;, could perform to an empty audience and still have
a good time. The multi-instrumentalist soloist joked he almost quit music on
account of his bandmates, and when the microphone kept drooping from its stand,
he drew comparisons between his relationship to the microphone to that of a
romantic one. ‘Rocky start, but those sometimes lead to the best ones.’ He
added, ‘Let’s see how it goes tonight.’ Even a failed explanation of why a song
about Norway was funny because Norwegen sounds similar to something else in
German, was rescued when he looked at the crowd of confused Danes and
deadpanned, ‘It’s funny.’ And even if it wasn’t funny (thought it was), it was
deranged, unhinged, mid-range crushingly good ol’ fun. Stupid synths with
laughable lines and big bad beats squelched at the remains of a crowd shook
loose from all inhibitions. More please, we begged, when he tried wrapping up.
For the first time, he was the one perplexed, wracking his brain to come up
with additions to his setlist. We danced and danced and begged not to be left
to the charge of DJ something-or-other to mop up the sweaty dregs of the
festival.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Though both Föllakzoid and Chris Imler put on great performances, it was the
first act who I saw on Saturday, &lt;b&gt;Baby In Vain&lt;/b&gt;, who were the stand-out show of
Northern Winter Beat 2024. They shared a timeslot with Deerhoof, the festival’s
headliners, but having discovered Baby In Vain’s Got It In You on an Iceage
playlist a couple of months earlier, I opted for the creators of my favourite
song of 2023. The trio of drummer and two guitarists are the real deal. They
exuded an effortless cool and a calmness of having been there, done that,
despite their relative youth. Their friendship was palpable and they invited
the audience in to their haven. The two frontwomen switched up lead vocals:
Andrea’s were prettier, Lola’s were grittier. Throughout, Benedicte messed with
time, slowling down the beat until it fell apart, before haphazardly gathering
up the pieces together again. Meanwhile, guitars purposely sabotaged solos, and
the bandmates grinned wildly at each other at the end result. My partner had
accompanied me for this one act, and we kept checking in with one another,
‘They are really good, aren’t they? They’re really really good.’ Each song
confirmed our suspicions more and more and more.
&lt;/p&gt;

        </description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <title>Yes, we saw Swans last night</title>
        <link>https://christianchristiansen.net/log/swans.html</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 07:58:06 AEDT</pubDate>
        <guid>
        https://christianchristiansen.net/log/swans.html
        </guid>
        <description>

&lt;h1 class=&quot;title&quot;&gt;Yes, we saw Swans last night&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
We’d heard the forecast: inclemency on Tuesday evening. A couple hundred
townsfolk gathered outside the local church in anticipation. All of us had
heard rumours of the impending phenomenon. Its might was legendary. Newspaper
clippings from survivors in America warned of incineration, annihilation, and
worse. But despite the evidence of destruction and land laid to waste,
first-hand witnesses gave reverential accounts, fear and awe burned into their
eyes.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The church doors opened and we filed in, the offer of bread and wine replaced
by ear plugs. We said thanks, but we’d come prepared. The doorman smirked. Red
light bathed the atrium, dimly lighting up a painting at the fore of Christ,
with his arms outstretched, ready to embrace his followers. Ten candles
flickered, patient as uneasiness grew. A church representative took to the
front, clearly delighted by the turn out. What we will witness today… his words
trailed off as his face brightened and morphed and fell as the full weight of
fate became clear to him. He yelped and scurried off, and soon the first
tremors took hold.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The phenomenon would be preceded by a separate, milder before-shock, we had
been warned by the forecasts. It thrashed and howled, twisting before us. But
we had seen its like before. No surprise. No fear. Calm settled again. We
half-smiled at each other, complacent.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
And then it hit. An attack on all sensations. Swirls of cacophony heaped on
cacophony burst apart reason and possibilities of experience. Our bodies rocked
cowed into submission, though our eyes were wide, wild even, desperately
seeking some answer, any answer, any semblance of coherence within this
maelstrom. But the storm continued unrelenting, oblivious to our measly
worries. What perceptions remained simply registered more. Increase. Thought it
was more than there had ever been, it was still more. More. Forever revving up.
Then the fear kicked in, it was true, there was only one way out: face the
music. Try to survive.
&lt;/p&gt;

        </description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <title>Hurt</title>
        <link>https://christianchristiansen.net/log/hurt.html</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 01:29:19 AEDT</pubDate>
        <guid>
        https://christianchristiansen.net/log/hurt.html
        </guid>
        <description>

&lt;h1 class=&quot;title&quot;&gt;Hurt&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
God is dead proclaims a coked up Nietzsche on stage. And no one cares responds
the congregation, writhing in unison, thrashing the air, spilling testosterone
into the arena which sloshes between the stage and the bullpit, infecting those
gathered into a state of existential bliss.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Raucous applause follows Nietzsche shuffling off and an old man shuffling on.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The old man ignores the crowd before him; they have yet their lives ahead,
lessons to learn and mistakes to make, symbols to desecrate, authority to
ruffle and then obtain, hope and despair to lose and gain; but he has seen the
birth of his children and their children and their children; and he himself was
born into a world in which he played and made pacts with other boys to another
day of chasing through the cotton fields, to keep secrets kept, to summers
unchanging, to camaraderie forever; but another day passed and went and now
those cotton fields are no longer, the secrets long cast aside, the seasons
shifted, the boys turned men drifted apart and taken away: camaraderie forever
– cut short. And that world is gone, and in its place, worlds appeared, passed
by, crumbled and faded. Yet he is here.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
He stands, palms open, and looks death in the eye. What have I become? he asks.
It is for us to respond.
&lt;/p&gt;

        </description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <title>A case for copyleft</title>
        <link>https://christianchristiansen.net/log/a-case-for-copyleft.html</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2023 15:18:20 AEST</pubDate>
        <guid>
        https://christianchristiansen.net/log/a-case-for-copyleft.html
        </guid>
        <description>

&lt;h1 class=&quot;title&quot;&gt;A case for copyleft&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;table-of-contents&quot; role=&quot;doc-toc&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Table of Contents&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;text-table-of-contents&quot; role=&quot;doc-toc&quot;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#org340de95&quot;&gt;What is a software licence?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#orgb3ae795&quot;&gt;The legal default: proprietary&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#orga3602ef&quot;&gt;Free (as in freedom) software&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#orgb59d86f&quot;&gt;Permissive&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#orgc3b2c18&quot;&gt;Copyleft&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;outline-container-org340de95&quot; class=&quot;outline-2&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;org340de95&quot;&gt;What is a software licence?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;outline-text-2&quot; id=&quot;text-org340de95&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Coding is difficult. Communicating a set of instructions to an overly pedantic
machine and dealing with the aftermath – the misplaced comma, the fallacies in
your logic, the unplugged cable, the pervasive self-doubt – is no sane person’s
idea of easy. But coding is also fun. The ability to communicate a set of
instructions to a machine, which will execute precisely what you have
instructed, and to see the exact product of your thought, is intensely
gratifying.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The programmer, like the poet, works only slightly removed from pure
thought-stuff. She&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;fnr.1&quot; class=&quot;footref&quot; href=&quot;#fn.1&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; builds her castles in the air, from air, creating by
exertion of the imagination. […] One types the correct incantation on a
keyboard, and a display screen comes to life, showing things that never were
nor could be.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;quoter&quot;&gt;Fred Brooks, The Mythical Man Month&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
A licence sets the terms and conditions of how others may interact with your
thought-stuff. May they look at it? Touch it? Prod it? May they play with it?
Adapt it to their own needs? Make money with it? And if they improve it, do
they have to share those improvements with you?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;outline-container-orgb3ae795&quot; class=&quot;outline-2&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;orgb3ae795&quot;&gt;The legal default: proprietary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;outline-text-2&quot; id=&quot;text-orgb3ae795&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
As with all copyright, by default, anything you create belongs to you. If you
write code, nobody else may use it, play with it, sniff it. This evidently
sucks. The first hackers&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;fnr.2&quot; class=&quot;footref&quot; href=&quot;#fn.2&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; flagrantly disregarded these limitations:
they stayed up all night sharing ideas, code, thoughts, theories, computing
time, and Chinese sweet-and-sour bitter melon. Military sponsors (who are
accustomed to secrecy) understandably balked, as did those who were primarily
interested in money. (The future richest person in the world, Bill Gates,
denounced this culture of sharing in An Open Letter to Hobbyists, denouncing
hobbyists as thieves.) Software should be closed and locked away. Software
should be proprietary. Sharing and caring be damned.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
As a reaction against closed software, hackers gathered to defend their culture
of openness and sharing, and created an alternative: free and open source
software.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;outline-container-orga3602ef&quot; class=&quot;outline-2&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;orga3602ef&quot;&gt;Free (as in freedom) software&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;outline-text-2&quot; id=&quot;text-orga3602ef&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Free and open source software&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;fnr.3&quot; class=&quot;footref&quot; href=&quot;#fn.3&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; licences allow users to share, to play
with, to modify, to monetise code. Free and open source software powers the 100
fastest supercomputers, roves on Mars, underpins the Internet, runs on most
phones. Amazon, Microsoft, Meta (Facebook) and Alphabet (Google), all fervent
users of free and open source software, made a combined gross profit of over
$600 billion in 2022.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Free and open source software licences come in two flavours: permissive and
copyleft. Permissive says: do whatever the hell you want to do with
it. Copyleft says: do whatever the hell you want to do with it, but allow
others to do whatever the hell they want to do with it too.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;outline-container-orgb59d86f&quot; class=&quot;outline-2&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;orgb59d86f&quot;&gt;Permissive&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;outline-text-2&quot; id=&quot;text-orgb59d86f&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
GitHub, bought by Microsoft in 2018, is the world’s largest host of free and
open source software. Developers gather to share code, ideas, issues and fixes.
It is the first port of call for developers to start a new project, and the
overwhelming number of projects use a permissive licence.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Why? The owner, Microsoft, uses MIT, a permissive licence. Other big players –
Google, Amazon, Apple, Facebook – use permissive licences too. They benefit
from inculcating a culture of permissive licences, as it allows them to reap
the benefits of using volunteers’ code, having volunteers fix their bugs and
write new features, and to simply close off access when it suits them. Copyleft
is viral&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;fnr.4&quot; class=&quot;footref&quot; href=&quot;#fn.4&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. Copyleft is a cancer&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;fnr.5&quot; class=&quot;footref&quot; href=&quot;#fn.5&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. Copyleft scares users
off from using the code. Is that so?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;outline-container-orgc3b2c18&quot; class=&quot;outline-2&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;orgc3b2c18&quot;&gt;Copyleft&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;outline-text-2&quot; id=&quot;text-orgc3b2c18&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Copyleft stipulates that our freedoms are non-negotiable. You have the right to
use my software, to modify it, to share it. But if you share it, you must grant
the person you share the software with those same freedoms: they too must be
allowed to use the software, to modify it, to share it. You are unable to
restrict those freedoms in any way.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Copyleft is so simple, so idealistic, so compelling, it seems impossible that
it could work. Detractors have probed for loopholes, a fault in the logic.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Would I be able to charge the other person? How about if so much of the ship
changed, every part is new, is the ship still copyleft? Do I still have to
provide those freedoms if an emu is chasing me? What about on a Tuesday?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
To soothe all of these fears and block up any cracks, the best copyleft
licence, the GNU AGPL, runs to 5535 words. Still though, questions come, and
all-encompassing statements:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
No one could make money off of it. No company would dare touch it. Nothing so
morally naïve could survive in the ‘real’ world. Take your head out of the
clouds, clear your mind of ‘thought-stuff’, this ain’t gonna work.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Yet, copyleft powers the 100 fastest supercomputers, roves on Mars, underpins
the Internet, runs on most phones. Amazon, Microsoft, Meta (Facebook) and
Alphabet (Google), all heavy users of copyleft software, made a combined gross
profit of over $600 billion in 2022.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The case for copyleft is clear. Coding is difficult, but we can share the
burden. Let us share the fun too.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;Footnotes: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;text-footnotes&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footdef&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;fn.1&quot; class=&quot;footnum&quot; href=&quot;#fnr.1&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;footpara&quot; role=&quot;doc-footnote&quot;&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;footpara&quot;&gt;
As was more common in 1975, Fred Brooks used the male pronoun as the
neutral default. The male default rankles with me, however, so I’ve tweaked the
pronouns. See:
&lt;a href=&quot;https://thesocietypages.org/socimages/2013/02/16/male-as-the-neutral-default/&quot;&gt;https://thesocietypages.org/socimages/2013/02/16/male-as-the-neutral-default/&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footdef&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;fn.2&quot; class=&quot;footnum&quot; href=&quot;#fnr.2&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;footpara&quot; role=&quot;doc-footnote&quot;&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;footpara&quot;&gt;
hacker: A person who delights in having an intimate understanding
of the internal workings of a system, computers and computer networks in
particular. G. Malkin, RFC 1392: the Internet Users’ Glossary.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footdef&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;fn.3&quot; class=&quot;footnum&quot; href=&quot;#fnr.3&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;footpara&quot; role=&quot;doc-footnote&quot;&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;footpara&quot;&gt;
As in any other sphere with heated ideological differences, there are
many terms used to describe essentially the same concept. Free software, the
original term, is favoured by idealists. Open source was created by pragmatists
who were worried that the term free was being misunderstood and was scaring off
businesses. Open source is now the most commonly used term. Free and open
source software, a lengthy and unwieldly compromise, is preferred by those who
adopt pretensions of idealism, but are too cowardly to fully commit. Other
alternatives, such as free libre and open source software (FLOSS), have even
more obvious flaws.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footdef&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;fn.4&quot; class=&quot;footnum&quot; href=&quot;#fnr.4&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;footpara&quot; role=&quot;doc-footnote&quot;&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;footpara&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/readme/guides/open-source-licensing&quot;&gt;https://github.com/readme/guides/open-source-licensing&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footdef&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;fn.5&quot; class=&quot;footnum&quot; href=&quot;#fnr.5&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;footpara&quot; role=&quot;doc-footnote&quot;&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;footpara&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/2001/06/02/ballmer_linux_is_a_cancer/&quot;&gt;https://www.theregister.com/2001/06/02/ballmer_linux_is_a_cancer/&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
        </description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <title>Markdown + CSS + Pandoc</title>
        <link>https://christianchristiansen.net/log/markdown-css-pandoc.html</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 06 May 2023 14:26:34 AEST</pubDate>
        <guid>
        https://christianchristiansen.net/log/markdown-css-pandoc.html
        </guid>
        <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Kære Tøger,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;out-with-the-old&quot;&gt;Out with the old&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The specifications of HTML (and CSS) have greatly matured since the
days of Macromedia Shockwave and &lt;code
class=&quot;blink&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;blink&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; tags. Even JavaScript has become more
sane, admittedly from a low starting base (see &lt;a
href=&quot;https://www.destroyallsoftware.com/talks/wat&quot;&gt;wat&lt;/a&gt;). Yet few
people today would propose writing articles in HTML: closing tags are
cumbersome, naming body parts in code seems outdated, angle brackets –
despite their winsome aesthetic – are out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;kiss-principle&quot;&gt;KISS principle&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Markdown&lt;/strong&gt;, a minimal markup language designed to
compile to HTML, is the favoured replacement to HTML for articles,
essays and other long-form writing amongst current techy scribblers (at
least amongst those who have yet to discover the one true way of Emacs
and Org-mode). The syntax is ludicrously simple and requires no
explanation (see the &lt;a
href=&quot;https://docs.github.com/en/get-started/writing-on-github/getting-started-with-writing-and-formatting-on-github/basic-writing-and-formatting-syntax&quot;&gt;primer&lt;/a&gt;
by GitHub). Write in your preferred text editor, and save it with the
extension &lt;code&gt;.md&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Too easy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;quoter&quot;&gt;
– said some person once.
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;shapeshifting&quot;&gt;Shapeshifting&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://pandoc.org&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pandoc&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, created by
a philosopher named &lt;a href=&quot;https://johnmacfarlane.net&quot;&gt;John
MacFarlane&lt;/a&gt;, is the best program for converting text files from one
format to another. To convert &lt;code&gt;input.md&lt;/code&gt; to
&lt;code&gt;output.html&lt;/code&gt;, type the following into your favourite
terminal:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sourceCode&quot; id=&quot;cb1&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;sourceCode sh&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;sourceCode bash&quot;&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;cb1-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#cb1-1&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;ex&quot;&gt;pandoc&lt;/span&gt; input.md &lt;span class=&quot;at&quot;&gt;-o&lt;/span&gt; output.html&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those are the basics covered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;form-and-substance&quot;&gt;Form and substance&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To add pizzazz, we require &lt;strong&gt;Cascading Style Sheets
(CSS)&lt;/strong&gt;. To include a link to a CSS stylesheet, use the following
option with Pandoc:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sourceCode&quot; id=&quot;cb2&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;sourceCode sh&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;sourceCode bash&quot;&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;cb2-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#cb2-1&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;ex&quot;&gt;pandoc&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;at&quot;&gt;-s&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;at&quot;&gt;--css&lt;/span&gt; style.css input.md &lt;span class=&quot;at&quot;&gt;-o&lt;/span&gt; output.html&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;thats-all-folks&quot;&gt;That’s all folks!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Das war’s. Of course, there are many rabbit holes one can end up
going down, but remember, the purpose of using Markdown in the first
place is to keep as much syntax (and distraction) away as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keep writing. 加油！ Any questions, ask me – I’ll gladly answer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;postscriptum&quot;&gt;Postscriptum&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Markdown and CSS of this post are available &lt;a
href=&quot;./markdown-css-pandoc.md&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a
href=&quot;../main.css&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. To re-create the post, type in the
following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sourceCode&quot; id=&quot;cb3&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;sourceCode sh&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;sourceCode bash&quot;&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;cb3-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#cb3-1&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;ex&quot;&gt;pandoc&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;at&quot;&gt;-s&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;at&quot;&gt;--css&lt;/span&gt; main.css &lt;span class=&quot;dt&quot;&gt;\&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span id=&quot;cb3-2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#cb3-2&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;markdown-css-pandoc.md &lt;span class=&quot;at&quot;&gt;-o&lt;/span&gt; markdown-css-pandoc.html&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note: for the correct fonts to be used, you will need &lt;a
href=&quot;../fonts/Roboto_Mono/RobotoMono-Regular.ttf&quot;&gt;RobotoMono&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a
href=&quot;../fonts/EBGaramond-0.016/ttf/EBGaramond12-Regular.ttf&quot;&gt;EBGaramond&lt;/a&gt;
to be in the relative paths as determined by &lt;code&gt;font-face&lt;/code&gt; in
the CSS file.&lt;/p&gt;

        </description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <title>Øresund Øffensiv</title>
        <link>https://christianchristiansen.net/log/øresund-øffensiv.html</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2023 16:26:56 AEST</pubDate>
        <guid>
        https://christianchristiansen.net/log/øresund-øffensiv.html
        </guid>
        <description>

&lt;h1 class=&quot;title&quot;&gt;Øresund Øffensiv&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The heat hit first. Emanating from the mass of bodies, it clung to our
skin as we dithered along the aisle, looking for free seats in the
cinema-cum-sauna. We found two too near to the screen, draped clean towels over
the burgundy upholstery, sat down and shuffled out of our clothes.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
‘Good evening folks! Welcome to Ritz Cinemas and our first showing of &lt;i&gt;Nude
Tuesday&lt;/i&gt;! As some of you may have already gathered, this is a clothing-optional
showing. If this wasn’t communicated to you beforehand or you are feeling
uncomfortable, please do let me – or one of our helpers here this evening –
know. I’m sure we can get you to a screening of – I don’t know – &lt;i&gt;Top Gun&lt;/i&gt; or
something else instead. There will also be other clothing-mandatory times you
can catch this film too – don’t worry.’
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The MC continued to soothe and explain and clarify and take the edge off of the
jitteriness in the room. After some final words and applause,
the ads began to roll. We held each other’s hands, ecstatic with the novelty.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The spoken gibberish is subtitled in English. The acting carries the
story; the subtitles buttress the laughter. A scene of a wife rejecting her
husband’s advances doubles its laughs once we read what her excuse is. When her
mother then gets nosy and tries to help with the situation, the comedy
comes from both the innuendo in gibberish, and its translation. A soaring
sonorous poem by the sex guru played by Jermaine Clement is later rendered
flacid and pathetic in English. The miscommunication, the subtitles, the
gibberish – it’s hilarious.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The gibberish is faux-Scandi. Prior to filming, the Kiwi actors had listened
to Icelandic radio for two weeks straight, and attempted to not sound too
French, too Italian, too Greek. The choice of Nordic was astute, not only
because Northern Europeans are notoriously comfortable in the nude, but also
because the Nordic languages have a long history of miscommunication.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Norwegians, for example, cannot agree on how to write their language, and have
created &lt;i&gt;riksmål&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;bokmål&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;nynorsk&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;høgnorsk&lt;/i&gt; and many other shades of
&lt;i&gt;måls&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;norsks&lt;/i&gt; inbetween. Another example is Cnut, King of Denmark
between 1018 and 1035, whose musings on the tide dumbfounded not only his
contemporaries but has also had historians, linguists and philosophers
scratching their heads for almost a millenium. (Ironically, Cnut’s grandfather
Harald Blåtand, King of Denmark c. 958 – c. 986, is the namesake of the
communications protocol Bluetooth.)
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The best example of Nordic confusion though stems from Norwegian television.
&lt;i&gt;Uti vår hage&lt;/i&gt;, a Norwegian show named after a Swedish folk song, filmed a
documentary of life in Denmark in 2003, revealing how Danes were no longer able
to communicate with one another in Danish. In the footage, a Dane attempts to
buy a new bike tyre, but ends up with a kamelåså instead.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
For me, the Danish language has collapsed into meaningless guttural sounds.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;quoter&quot;&gt;An unhappy customer, Episode 1, Uti vår
hage&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
When the documentary first aired in Denmark, it was wrongly interpreted to be a
spoof and Swedes were wrongly identified to be the culprits. Danish protestors
lined the shore facing Sweden and launched sausages across the strait. Swedes
retaliated with meatballs. The ongoing Øresund Øffensiv remains to be
the major obstacle to Swedish ascession to NATO.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
After the film and dressed again, my partner and I debriefed over a
fake-herring smörgåsbord and salmon smørresbrød at &lt;i&gt;Feilkommunikasjon&lt;/i&gt;.
‘Läcker,’ my partner grinned, savouring the lingonberry jam. ‘I really enjoyed
the film.’
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
‘Me too,’ I agreed.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
‘The choice of Nordic was particularly apt,’ she expounded, ‘given how
prevalent miscommunication in that region is. Take, for example, the Öresund
Öffensiv, where the Swedes started throwing pannbiff at the Danes. The
Danes retaliated with frikadellen. It all started with a Finnish TV
documentary…’
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
‘Wasn’t it…’ I butt in, but she is having none of it. I stand my ground.
She retaliates, so I throw salmon and she throws herring and covers me in
lingonberry jam but wham what a shot but oh no her towel and we shout at one
another across straits descending into meaningless guttural sounds, gibbering
away.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I look at us both, ryebreaded and leverpostejed, and ask, ‘What are we fighting
about again?’
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
She blinks and looks at me. ‘I don’t know – it’s all Greek to me.’
&lt;/p&gt;

        </description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <title>A new pet</title>
        <link>https://christianchristiansen.net/log/a-new-pet.html</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2023 22:37:22 AEDT</pubDate>
        <guid>
        https://christianchristiansen.net/log/a-new-pet.html
        </guid>
        <description>

&lt;h1 class=&quot;title&quot;&gt;A new pet&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Isabella, popular Isabella, got one first. Her aunt in the Alps had gifted it
to her, after a trip to see the spring blossom. ‘I’m sorry about your hamster,’
she had said, ‘I’m sure it can never be replaced,’ she had continued, ‘but here
is a new… all the way from Japan… it’s like a pet, and you’ll have to take care
of
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
‘Gerbil’
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
‘I’m sorry?’
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
‘It was my gerbil. Jeremiah.’
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
‘Well here’s a &lt;i&gt;tomogochee&lt;/i&gt;​… all the way from Japan…’
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
And we crowded around Isabella when she first brought it to the playground.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
‘What is it?’
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
‘Is it a Digimon?’
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
‘Does it speak?’
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
‘Does it fart?’
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Isabella held her chin high, above the sniggers, and slowly bestowed her
snippets of wisdom. She prodded the new thing and the new thing squeaked. We
squealed with excitement, and envy. ‘It’s a &lt;i&gt;tomato-chee&lt;/i&gt;,’ she explained, ‘and
it doesn’t fart. It poos.’
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The next day, Hannah had one. The Monday after, James, Miriam, Luke, Megan,
Other James, Olly, Meg 2, Leela and Chloe also had one. Soon, everybody else
had stopped kicking a ball about or skipping or gossipping, they were all
caring for their new pets. After bargaining with Meg 2 and promising her I
wouldn’t ever tell anybody that – ah, you almost got me – I got one too. It was
pink, it had three buttons, it was a bit scuffed on the left side, and it was
mine.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I cradled the blobular avatar, I watched its mouth open and close, I pressed
the three buttons and gawped unknowingly at the undecipherable symbols floating
on screen. I was happy. Two days later, it was dead.
&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div id=&quot;org086e1cf&quot; class=&quot;figure&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;./a-new-pet.webp&quot; alt=&quot;a-new-pet.webp&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Nowadays, I have multiple Tamagotchis and have learnt their languages of beeps
and symbols. I nurture them and nurse them; I keep them alive. At home, I have
two big Tamagotchis who are fairly low maintenance: they need occasional
updating, a few parts replacing, an occasional scrub. Nothing much. I’ve given
sufficient vaccinations to one so that it no longer requires antivirus. My
housemates and I fawn over the other one. Most evenings we prepare our dinners
and eat our food sitting on the sofa in its glowing presence for hours on end.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
A smaller Tamagotchi lives in my pocket and sleeps under my pillow. It purrs
and buzzes, flashes and blinks. I tend to it fifty times a day: checking its
status, keeping it topped up, silencing it when it all becomes too much. But
it’s my newest Tamagotchi I’m most excited about. It’s strapped to my wrist and
knows all about me. I’m outside playing football, it deduces. My heart is
beating at 132 beats per minute, it informs me. I’ve walked more than the
target it’s set for me, it congratulates me. Low battery, it lets me know.
Please charge me, it demands. I stop with the ball and stare at the back of my
wrist. Charge me, it demands. I stare. Charge. Me. I unstrap the Tamagotchi. I
feel its metal weight. I hold it in my hands, and I watch it die.
&lt;/p&gt;

        </description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <title>That time of the year</title>
        <link>https://christianchristiansen.net/log/that-time-of-the-year.html</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2022 20:26:21 AEDT</pubDate>
        <guid>
        https://christianchristiansen.net/log/that-time-of-the-year.html
        </guid>
        <description>

&lt;h1 class=&quot;title&quot;&gt;That time of the year&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The signs had been there. The red and green beach balls. The notices from HR.
The upcoming events. The planning, the organisation, the planning the
organisation. My local magpie had told me the other day that the eastern koels
were back, yapping on about their time spent in Queensland – it couldn’t wait
for the koels to go back, if they thought it was so bloody good there. Or
that’s what I imagined the magpie saying, as it squawked in my face on the
balcony causing me to spill my morning eggnog.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
It had been coming. This time I was more prepared. I had done the shopping, the
careful filtering out of anything too tacky, too lavish, too unfair, too pink,
too blue, too heavy, too cheap, too expensive, too immoral, too moral, too
passé – a yo-yo and Tamagotchi just don’t cut it anymore. I had done the
shopping, bought appropiately themed wrapping paper, felt both guilty and
proud of the resulting packages, and shipped off the goodies with (hopefully)
ample time. Then there were more trips to the post office to pick up gifts
with cards from faraway relatives and well-wishers. The cards vie with
the flowers for space on top of the piano; the gifts nestle beneath a tree
comprised primarily of cardboard, green felt-tip pen marks and good intentions.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
But it arrived today. &lt;i&gt;Oops, I did it again&lt;/i&gt; was my most listened to track of
the year, a music streaming service informs me. These were the films I should
have watched, a columnist lets me know. I open a little door to reveal
a drawing of a festive animal in festive attire. I eat a square of chocolate. I
race other programmers to solve a puzzle about calorie-counting elves. Joy to
the world. The silly season is here.
&lt;/p&gt;

        </description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <title>Glebe</title>
        <link>https://christianchristiansen.net/log/glebe.html</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2022 11:36:06 AEDT</pubDate>
        <guid>
        https://christianchristiansen.net/log/glebe.html
        </guid>
        <description>

&lt;h1 class=&quot;title&quot;&gt;Glebe&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;verse&quot;&gt;
chairs deck the tarmac&lt;br /&gt;
where the cars used to be&lt;br /&gt;
flickering in and out of light&lt;br /&gt;
filtered through the leaves of a tree&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
a party atmosphere pervades&lt;br /&gt;
the parade&lt;br /&gt;
this saturday&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
a trio provide a sonic background&lt;br /&gt;
upon which&lt;br /&gt;
a child’s laugh&lt;br /&gt;
a bird’s squawk&lt;br /&gt;
an enthusiastic embrace&lt;br /&gt;
dance and pirouette&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
hand in hand&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
we reach the restaurant&lt;br /&gt;
far past the market&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
there’s nothing vegan&lt;br /&gt;
we umm and ahh&lt;br /&gt;
and dawdle across&lt;br /&gt;
to a stand&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
of pretty books&lt;br /&gt;
outside a gallery&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I pick one up&lt;br /&gt;
about here&lt;br /&gt;
about Glebe&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
local&lt;br /&gt;
Anna Couani&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
she looks at me&lt;br /&gt;
she says&lt;br /&gt;
that’s me&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

        </description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <title>A review of A Collection of Reviews</title>
        <link>https://christianchristiansen.net/log/a-review-of-a-collection-of-reviews.html</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2022 07:29:46 AEDT</pubDate>
        <guid>
        https://christianchristiansen.net/log/a-review-of-a-collection-of-reviews.html
        </guid>
        <description>

&lt;h1 class=&quot;title&quot;&gt;A review of A Collection of Reviews&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I had finished sipping my orange green tea and set off back to the station,
when a blockade in the pavement of books for 5 dollars stopped me. The Agatha
Christie’s reeled me in, but my nose led me away, into the shop. Suddenly, I
was confronted by vast stacks of porcelain knick-knacks, sculpted felines
serving as bowls, pots and other vessels to hold pumpkin soup and sour cream on
a pleasant Georgian recreational summer’s day. I froze. Luckily, I spotted a
sign by some steps to the basement promising books.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
As I descended the stairs, my eyes feasted upon lines upon lines of the goods.
A motley assortment of texts sliced the room into partitions; each partition
fielded a powerful possé of mouthpieces for its allotted subject: Australian
history, experimental French literature, gardening and garden allotments.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
When I finally reached the literary criticism section, searching for &lt;i&gt;The
Over-Abundance of Unnecessary Literary Examples Within Literature&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Get To
The Point&lt;/i&gt;, I spotted a white tome: &lt;i&gt;A Collection of Book Reviews&lt;/i&gt; by Andrea
C. Hansdatter. The collection didn’t have a price, and the shopkeeper appeared
to be baffled by its presence, so I offered to relieve her of her bafflement
and book for 5 bucks.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
It has been consuming me ever since. The collection appears to order the books
first by author surname, and then by publication date. However this system is
already abandoned at Atwood, where Hansdatter proceeds to review Orwell,
Huxley, Zamyatin, More and a slew of other dystopian/utopian fiction. Indeed,
in the review of &lt;i&gt;A Handmaid’s Tale&lt;/i&gt;, a commentary about the novelty of seeing
a dystopia from predominantly an individual’s perspective as opposed to from a
greater societal view, is sidelined by a vehement critique, in which Hansdatter
chastises &lt;i&gt;1984&lt;/i&gt; for pillaging &lt;i&gt;We&lt;/i&gt; of its plot and characters, and eschewing
the radical innovative narrative language and changing the power dynamic of the
central couple to the detriment of the woman. Hansdatter lambasts Orwell’s
other work too, though I suspect she has not read them (aside from perhaps
&lt;i&gt;Animal Farm&lt;/i&gt;); this is based off of a hunch, however, as I have not read them
yet either.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The reviews vary greatly in style, length, comprehensability, accuracy and
taste, much like the books reviewed. However, common threads do shine through.
Hansdatter often begins with some background on how she came across the book.
She’s forever travelling from one place to another, sampling exotic
delicatessen, being barraged by sudden apparitions of &lt;i&gt;Sherlock Holmes&lt;/i&gt;
compilations. Infuriatingly, we never find out why her baguette is red, nor
what her destination is; her train of thought is always interrupted by a review
of a book.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Certain frames of reference pop up consistently too. Although Hansdatter is not
as profligate as say Quentin Tarantino or Mark Fisher in plucking esoteric
references from Japanese action films or Japanese cyberpunk anime, she will
happily name-drop Tarantino and Fisher, without introduction, to make a point
clear. She is particularly fond of using examples from her personal life,
Hans C. Andersen’s stories, and quips from an imaginary friend.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Pithy, short, cutting statements dot Hansdatter’s collection. The entry for
&lt;i&gt;Little Women&lt;/i&gt; states: ‘Eat forty seven heaped spoonfuls of sugar to
achieve a similar effect.’ On &lt;i&gt;Lord of the Rings&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Dune&lt;/i&gt;, she writes:
‘Orcs and destiny are rather dull.’ The shortest review I have found so far, is
the entry for &lt;i&gt;Don Quixote&lt;/i&gt;: ‘The best.’
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Through her shifts in tone, her references, her favourites, her digressions, we
gradually piece together parts of Hansdatter’s personality, and the world she
inhabits. We learn of her love of Greece, and how on her first trip there she
saw ‘the perfect marriage of sea, land and sky; resplendent majesty to be
savoured whole’. We learn that she adores swimming outside, whether in a port
in Copenhagen, where she can smell the cinnamon buns crispening in the morning
winter sun; in a glacial lake in the Alps with her best friend, splashing in
the deep turquoise; or at Little Bay beach after a day painting the restless
seascape, musing on the words of the artist Maggi Hambling:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The sea – I suppose it is a metaphor for life and death, and recycling and all
of that. It is also very sexy. I mean, you see a distant wave gradually
fumbling about. Approaching, approaching, approaching, until it reaches the
shore. It is pretty orgasmic, when it crashes, when it dissolves.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
We do not learn who her favourite artist is, nor which piece of artwork she
holds dearest; but Hansdatter self-knowlingly and pain-stakingly describes
&lt;i&gt;Zeichenreihen&lt;/i&gt;, a painting by Vasily Kandinsky, in which Kandinsky lines up
all of his favourite motifs on shelves, proudly on display to his audience.
Like Kandinsky’s &lt;i&gt;Zeichenreiehn&lt;/i&gt;, Hansdatter’s reviews are full of her
favourite motifs, all lined up, stark, colourful, sharpened.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
We are treated to a plethora of these motifs in perhaps Hansdatter’s longest
review, her review of &lt;i&gt;Die Lebenden und die Toten&lt;/i&gt;, a crime story in German by
Nele Neuhaus. In the review, Hansdatter intersects a complete line-by-line
English translation with swathes of venom. Here is a taster:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
This is a characterless characterisation of a character without character. The
language is bland. The character is bland. It leaves me salivating for dry bark
instead, splinters included.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
“She has been an Executive Partner at an international consultancy for eight
years, responsible for the restructuring and internationalisation of companies,
and two years ago she was assigned as the head of Management Consulting.”
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The lack of detail is conspicuous. Which international consultancy? For what
companies? Are there any positions and departments more vague than Executive
Partner and Management Consulting? Where’s the bark?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Hansdatter also includes a full translation of Franz Kafka’s &lt;i&gt;The
Metamorphosis&lt;/i&gt;. All previous translations of ‘ungeheurer Ungeziefer’ into
English did not quite sit right with her; she deemed them all to be ‘repulsive
monstrosities’. So she translated the phrase, then the first sentence, and then
simply continued until she had translated the whole novella. In my view,
Hansdatter’s translation is sublime, as sublime as any I can imagine.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Whether these two are her only reviews to include full original translations, I
do not know. There is no contents page, and the index appears to have
been plagiarised word for word from the index of &lt;i&gt;Index, A History of the&lt;/i&gt;. The
only reliable method to find a review of a specific book within the collection
is to flick through and spot its italicised name.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
And that is driving me mad. The longer I read &lt;i&gt;A Collection of Book Reviews&lt;/i&gt;,
the more convinced I am that Hansdatter is furiously editing it as I read it. I
had thought that Hansdatter had neglected to mention &lt;i&gt;La Disparation&lt;/i&gt;, but when
I check it now, it is right there, in its correct alphabetical place. And the
review for &lt;i&gt;The Very Hungry Caterpillar&lt;/i&gt; has gained wings and vanished into the
very air. To catch the text shape-shifting, I have purchased a scanner. To my
dismay, when I lay any page from the collection against the glass screen, the
scanner registers only blank page after blank page. But only for this one book;
it photocopies the UN’s Universal Declaration of Human Rights, passports and
currency fine, but those are of no use to me. To outsmart my book-bothering
trickster, I have started to keep the collection on my person at all times; I
sleep with the book beneath my pillow. This has brought about another issue:
stories I dream of during the night now appear reviewed in the book the day
after. Even for stories which are simply a figment of my imagination. I swear.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I am overcome with a sense of futility. How am I to review this book of
reviews, which expands as I sleep? Who am I to review this book of
reviews, to judge Hansdatter? Who am I to review a review of a book if
I have not read the book reviewed? Can I even have a valid opinion, if I have
never read Tolstoy and Joyce, &lt;i&gt;Hamlet&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Macbeth&lt;/i&gt;?
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Somewhere within the collection, Hansdatter forgets which book she is
reviewing, and wonders:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Why do I bother? However many books I read, it will be but a drop in the ocean.
What am I trying to do? Am I simply trying to add feathers to my tail, to
peacock around and attract a bespectacled mate, to prove my worth to some
unthinking reader or unknowing deity? I try to surf these waves of prose and
poetry to gaze at the heavens, to grasp at grounds for my existence, to not be
dragged down by the crashing rips which course over me; questions tear me
from every dimension. I grasp onto books, other humans’ defiant claims to
relevancy after death; I allow their ideas, preserved from cranium to ink, to
dance released again in my mind. I hope to glean another way, another path,
to understand this maelstrom of being, to see the world anew, again and ever
again.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Reading Hansdatter’s worries comforts me; another creature wrestles the same
demons. And rightfully so, I might add, for I have spotted a glaring hole in &lt;i&gt;A
Collection of Reviews&lt;/i&gt;. Despite her professed admiration of him, Andrea C.
Hansdatter has neglected to review any of Hans C. Andersen’s works. However,
Andrea C. Hansdatter has, inexplicably, somehow written a one sentence review
of &lt;i&gt;A review of A Collection of Reviews&lt;/i&gt; by C. C.:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
C. C., evidently, should have picked up an Agatha Christie instead.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

        </description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <title>Back for a holiday</title>
        <link>https://christianchristiansen.net/log/back-for-a-holiday.html</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2022 08:02:57 AEDT</pubDate>
        <guid>
        https://christianchristiansen.net/log/back-for-a-holiday.html
        </guid>
        <description>

&lt;h1 class=&quot;title&quot;&gt;Back for a holiday&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
A particular patriotic pride presided the passage to the pissoir. Upright men
of all ages stood tall in an orderly British queue. We filed in, awaited our
turn, and – as our forefathers had done in the Boer – carried out God’s duty,
before we filed back to refill and rearm ourselves for another round.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Ahead of me, two young gents shuffled along, bravely directing their attention
away from nature’s calling, aided by those smartphone devices. Their lit-up
faces the very picture of sangfroid, or was it ennui? A urinal became free, and
the first chap marched forth. The second pleaded to join in, as he was
‘bursting’. I am no socialist, but when I see a Brit extend favour to his
fellow countryman – as any good Anglican would – I well up. ‘God Save the
King!’ remarked I in admiration, slapping the pair of them, rugger style.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Another compatriot had become peckish during his journey from watering hole to
water closet. ‘I’ll have my cake and eat it’, the blonde mopped patron
proclaimed, before reaching in to sample the goods. He crunched and grinned,
beaming at his captive audience, foaming between his teeth.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
At last, my time had come. I proceeded, planted my two feet, and produced one
proud prick. Gushing with relief and bonhomie, I parleyed with my good
neighbour. ‘God bless you sir,’ greeted I. A steely glance was my reply.
Touché, nodded I in return. We are but men of few words. My salutation parried
and my business finished, I caught myself in the zip.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
‘God’s sake,’ muttered my son. ‘Again, Papa?’ he had said after I relayed my
story to him. ‘You know,’ he continued, ‘I think it’s time you moved back. You
haven’t been the same ever since you moved to Malaga.’
&lt;/p&gt;

        </description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <title>Wonderful world</title>
        <link>https://christianchristiansen.net/log/wonderful-world.html</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2022 13:32:16 AEDT</pubDate>
        <guid>
        https://christianchristiansen.net/log/wonderful-world.html
        </guid>
        <description>

&lt;h1 class=&quot;title&quot;&gt;Wonderful world&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The days were becoming shorter. Summer had been kind to us. Travelling from
loch to loch, broch to broch, Stewart and I spent sunrise to sunset soaking in
the Scottish sun, savouring the sharp contours of the landscape, the briskness,
the too real beauty surrounding us.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Stevie Wonder, Ella Fitzgerald, Brenda Lee sang through our stereo, as we
drove along the long, lonesome roads. It was just the two of us, the vast
sublime vistas, and the sweet sonorous Fifties and Sixties. Stewart would
repeatedly ask for The Bobbettes and I would put on &lt;i&gt;Mr Lee&lt;/i&gt;. His fat chubby
face would crinkle with joy and sing along with such glee. How I would flutter.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
On our walks I told childhood tales of walking across the moor and finding the
perfect song to match the hike, to match my emotions. Stewart would then recall
old comedy routines about Braveheart, about shortbread, offal and heroin.
Occasionally his brow would furrow with a quizzical look.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
There was a joke he was working on, about the Loch Ness monster. About
conspiracy theories and mistrust of experts. About how despite not having the
requisite knowledge in the relevant subjects, people jumped to such
strongly-held beliefs. But he couldn’t work out the structure, the form. A joke
is delicate, like a song, he explained once. The tiniest bit of inspiration
might be all that it takes. A breeze then blew the lines from his face and he
smiled at me again, and resumed telling me about the local history, the myths
and the Auld Alliance between the Scots and the French.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
… the French I took
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
But I do know that I love you &lt;br /&gt;
And I know that if you loved me, too &lt;br /&gt;
What a wonderful world this would be
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Sam Cooke’s lyrics washed over me as I watched Stewart delight in recalling
treaty details. I’ll show the song to him, I decided. That’s how I’ll let him
know. How I feel. What a wonderful world this would be.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Our final stop was Loch Ness. Summer had been kind to us. We sat by the shore,
a few puffy clouds in an ever bluer sky our only companions. I prepared, and
looked Stewart in the eye. My heart whined.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
‘Stew? I would like to play a song for you.’ I held out an earpiece. His hand
brushed against mine as he placed his earpiece into his ear, and I placed mine
into mine.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Don&#x27;t know much about history &lt;br /&gt;
Don&#x27;t know much biology &lt;br /&gt;
Don&#x27;t know much about a science book &lt;br /&gt;
Don&#x27;t know much about the French I took
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
But I do know that…
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
‘Yes, YES!’ he leaped.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
‘I’ve got the joke!’
&lt;/p&gt;

        </description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <title>Harry Potter and The Master and Margarita</title>
        <link>https://christianchristiansen.net/log/harry-potter-and-the-master-and-margarita.html</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2022 22:33:11 AEST</pubDate>
        <guid>
        https://christianchristiansen.net/log/harry-potter-and-the-master-and-margarita.html
        </guid>
        <description>

&lt;h1 class=&quot;title&quot;&gt;Harry Potter and The Master and Margarita&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
‘Are you feeling litigious?’
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
J. K. reponds with an empty smile. She brushes a loose strand of hair behind
her ear, and looks back out of the carriage window, staring into the space
between the pane and the Scottish fields sliding past. The dull scenery dances
through droplets which clutch onto the exterior for a while, before drifting
diagonally out of our vision.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
‘I feel litigious,’ butts in a broad voice. ‘Lawyer me up. When I go around
anywhere, I see copycats everywhere. I want barristers spilling out of my
holsters. I’m sick of seeing myself in this infernal fun house of mirrors. I’ll
sue them all, to hell and back. I’m the original fat cat. Humour me please, at
the very least: create a more trim version of me. Behind a couple of pounds of
this baby pudge, lies a rather cute pussy.’
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The behemoth of a cat across the aisle from J. K. and me pokes at its monstrous
belly, which bulges with such a gusto, unseen dimensions wobble to contain its
bulk. Sat facing the cat, is a mad-hatted man (well, who wears a fez these
days?) and betwixt this odd pair a chess game is in play.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The cat’s companion, the fez fellow, twists his long face towards J. K. and me.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
‘Comrades, please, excuse my friend. Behemoth here, he can be …’
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The fez bloke’s voice blurs into the background, as I become wholly absorbed by
the kittification of nightmare. Surely the cat didn’t just talk? Now, it (he?)
appears to be taking advantage of the fez man’s ongoing apology to J. K. and me
by furtively winking, twitching his (its?) whiskers and sticking his(?) tongue
out at his opponent’s pieces. One of the fez chap’s knight pieces deciphers
this unorthodox semaphoric display and assents; the souped-up tiny jockey
canters off the board and enjoys some well-deserved rest. The retired knight is
reportedly glad for a chance to stop horsing around.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
‘… rather prone to bouts of outbursts (and idioms). Apologies, again, comrades.
Good day.’
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
‘Call me a sack full of proverbs if you must, but I will not be restrained.
Till the cows come home, I will remain bullish. My tongue is as free as a bird,
like a bat out of hell; it flies like a butterfly and stings like a bee; as it
laps up milk and honey, it too will flap into battle, and slap slap slappity
slap any foe foe pho-munching foe. I’ll have it you, you twits.’
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
‘Behemoth, please, stop it now. There’s no need for this palaver. Let’s leave
our comrades in peace and return to our game.’
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
A miffed Behemoth, and the fezmeister, settle back down over the chessboard.
Confusion slowly spreads across the hatted man’s brow, as he inspects the
empty square where he could swear one of his knights should be.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I collect myself, and resolve not to look to my left again. &lt;i&gt;I’ll just pretend
they’re not there.&lt;/i&gt; J. K., opposite me, appears to be of the same mind. She is
desperately trying to distract herself by scribbling into a thin notepad. Below
a reminder to watch Star Wars again, and a line which reads &lt;i&gt;have the Defence
Against the Dark Arts teachers last as long as Spinal Tap drummers&lt;/i&gt;, I spot the
words &lt;i&gt;include living chess pieces like the crazy cat’s&lt;/i&gt; being added.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
‘Are you feeling litigious?’
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Tic-like, the question slips from my mouth again.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
‘Why?’ J. K. bites this time, covering her writing, annoyed, as if I have
asked some outrageous favour from her, as if I have asked whether I may tickle
her behind the knees, on a Tuesday.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
‘Well, I’ve been pondering a bit recently, about your work, and about
influences generally, really, and I, I couldn’t help but… well, you see, we
all… to be influenced is to be human, right? Ideas don’t just zoom into… out
of the blue…’
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
‘Ooh, look! Look! Fezzy fezster, check this out! Out the window!’ The cat has
lept onto his hind legs and is jumping up and down on his poor seat, jabbing a
paw at a… outside in the rain… a car? No. A flying car. ‘She’s coming to the
party! Woohoo!
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
‘Yoohoo! Margarita! Margarita!’ he continues to holler, waving his frying
pan-sized paw at the flying Ford Rossiya E501 Deluxe. From inside the
airborne vehicle, the so-hollered Margarita gives Behemoth two thumbs up,
beaming under her crooked hat. ‘I’ll see you at Woland(emort)’s,’ we read from
her lips.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
‘Ah, the new witch learns quick,’ booms the hat man. ‘Brooms are terribly
inconvenient, even the silk-padded ones. Cars are far superior. Back support is
not to be underestimated.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
‘And it is far too easy, awfully easy, to lose one’s headgear when
riding a broom. I have lost a plethora of fedoras, an array of berets; it is
how I have ended with this one, you see, the fez, to match my prince-nez.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
‘Automobiles, are they not just wonderful? I do enjoy a good train ride though,
comrades, it must be said. The characters you meet on a locomotive, they can be
truly remarkable.’
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Behemoth was too animated to notice his friend’s soliloquy. ‘I can’t wait for
Woland(emort)’s! The party will be the bee’s knees, the cat’s whiskers, the
dog’s …’
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
‘J. K., what I really mean is…,’ I struggle to tear my attention away from the
ongoing farce to my left. It has all gotten rather out of hand.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
‘What I mean is…,’ I plough on. ‘When does inspiration become plagiarism? Can
an idea be borrowed, or copied, or stolen? What are the differences? When is a
tip of a hat, more than that?’
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
‘And what the devil does that have to do with whether I’m feeling litigious or
not?’ J. K. bats back icily.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
‘Don’t misunderstand me, please, but I’m thinking of writing a piece… I
recently read The Master and Margarita by Mikhail Bulgakov and I couldn’t help
but notice some similarities between Bulgakov’s book and your own wizard ones…’
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
‘What are you going to do? Write: “Three things occur in both Harry Potter and
The Master and Margarita:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class=&quot;org-ol&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;living chess pieces;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;flying cars;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;travel by fireplace.”?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
You don’t need my permission for that. Anybody can do that. However, I confirm
and deny nothing.’
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
‘Well no… that’s not quite what I plan to do; bullet points would be a tad
bland. Also, I will have to mention somewhere (shoehorn if necessary) that The
Master and Margarita is Daniel Radcliffe’s favourite book. It’s too juicy a
fact to leave out. What I’m thinking of is possibly…’
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
‘What? Fictionalising me?’ she ponders, sucking against her teeth. A few tense
beats hang before she shrugs. ‘Hell, whatever. I’m a reasonable human being
with reasonable views. Do whatever you want,’ returning to twirling her Biro
and messing about with Professor (Lord) Woland(emort)’s name.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Relief and exhaustion seep through my body. A shudder… slides. I
focus on my breathing for some time. The pitter patter of rain has eased, and
the countryside outside is now English. The night has sidled up, with a cold
blanket, asking softly how my day has been. I try to look at my watch, to see
how long left of the journey there is, but my eyelids are too heavy. Gradually,
my ears are drawn, yet again, despite my earnest resolution, back to the
peculiar couple.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
‘Oi, Fezzer, remind me again. How are the rest of the gang getting to
Woland(emort)’s tonight?’ purrs Behemoth.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
‘Why? Have you not seen the chimney renovations? Surely you must be able to
figure it out by now.
&lt;/p&gt;

        </description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <title>Wellness Productivity</title>
        <link>https://christianchristiansen.net/log/wellness-productivity.html</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2022 03:42:07 AEST</pubDate>
        <guid>
        https://christianchristiansen.net/log/wellness-productivity.html
        </guid>
        <description>

&lt;h1 class=&quot;title&quot;&gt;Wellness Productivity&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
While following the scent of some sparkly stones, I have become trapped by
wall-high posters, shiny DVD cases; cursive, serif and sans-serif types
string me to an unseen ball and chain, dangling my prospects afore a row of
bared lips, which strain to contain the overflowing bleached whites within. One
by one the infinite smiles approach me. A clean bugle call precedes each
hovering mouth, ‘Please give a [Most Well And Distinguished Welcome] to our
[Honorable And High Distinguished Knowledger] on the [Affairs Of Life Of Humans
And Similar],’ joined in chorus by ethereal recommendations stemming from
unlocatable institutes and growth centres.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
‘If only I had heard from [] earlier, I may have never have had any issues with
my organic coffee cupholder.’
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
‘[] lays bare the secrets of the universe and more, and strips back the veil
from nature and beyond, and denudes the mist from everything itself and etc.’
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
‘I have bought multiple copies of []’s [], in order to digest the insights not
only aurally and visually, but nasally too. Listen, read and snort yourself to
enlightenment. Bless you.’
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The oncoming grin is accompanied by some other feature: a loose-fitting shirt,
a size-too-small skirt, a tie with both stripes and dots on of course to
indicate personality. Floating above sit the two same, dead eyes, boring into
my self-worth, mining me for nuggets to melt and fashion into a bangle, a nose
piercing, a monogrammed button, to adorn my latest life guide.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
‘Good Life, Dear Listener/Reader/Other Consumption Methoder. I am
Professor/Most Distinguished/Reviled By None/Envy Of The Mongeese
Smithy/Dharma/Valhallalala, Student/Learner of the Path/Road/Seaway to The
End/Wisdom/Valhallalala. I bring you gifts of Gold Standard Lessons in
Self/Unself/All-selves/Only-elves Respect and myrrh. I will Teach How to
Approach Your Journey, and Baby, You have just Started.’ A gush of canned
uplift muzak plays, and the learnings commence. Different smiles espouse
different aphorisms.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
‘Give me a Buddha, and I will give you a quote.’
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
‘The way to Live Laugh Love, is to Shift Shaft Shove.’
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
‘I am the walrus, goo-goo g’joob, g’goo goo g’joob, goo goo g’joob [copyright,
the Beatles].’
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
But every philosophy comes coated with the same layers upon layers of
justification. Not only do ceaseless recommendations riddle the
poster/book/DVD/other medium at hand, but validation from
history/tradition/science/religion (but only The Bible, Greek mythology and
Buddhism, maybe a sprinkling of Tao, and a quote from Gandhi of course) is also
hauled out, to tenuously brace the argument that there are 109 Methods to
Betterment Wellness Productivity.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I splutter. The fumes of mouthwash emanating from the parade of incisors brews
with smothering incense and the hanging musk of a spiritual gathering in my
nostrils; my body shuts. ‘Help!’ I shout. ‘Help me!’ More and more mouths spout
advice, more and more quirkily patterned cravats press forward to prescribe me
their experiences. Self-help books eagerly flap and wink their pages at me,
podcasters and influencers cast their lashes towards me. ‘Help me. Help,’ I
whimper. A friend answers. ‘What’s up buddy? Talk to me.’ And I do.
&lt;/p&gt;

        </description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <title>Heard whilst hyperventilating on Fiddlesticks, Organ Pipes</title>
        <link>https://christianchristiansen.net/log/heard-whilst-hyperventilating-on-fiddlesticks-organ-pipes.html</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jul 2022 18:56:14 AEST</pubDate>
        <guid>
        https://christianchristiansen.net/log/heard-whilst-hyperventilating-on-fiddlesticks-organ-pipes.html
        </guid>
        <description>

&lt;h1 class=&quot;title&quot;&gt;Heard whilst hyperventilating on Fiddlesticks, Organ Pipes&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Christian. Christian? Can you hear me? Christian… you’re safe. We’ve got you on
rope. Christian, talk to us. It’s all good. We’ve got you. Yes, yes. It’s
incredibly chossy. You don’t need to worry about us. We’re safe.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
You can do it. Keep going. Use those chimney skills. You can dangle the bag
between your legs, if you want to. Just keep moving. Christian. Christian?
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Yes, keep going. We’ve got you. Nic’s got you. Good work! Pull on those cams.
What’s that? There’s no more aid? Keep going. You can do it. What about the
foot to the left?
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Breathe, Christian, breathe. Christian, talk to us. Yes, it’s chossy. You’re
safe. Good work with the cam. You can leave the nuts in. You’re taking them
out? Good work. You can do it. Keep moving. Come on Christian.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
It’s still chossy? Don’t worry Christian. You’re doing well. Just keep moving.
Nice work. Really good work. Come on. Keep going. Breathe. Remember to breathe.
Nice work with the cam. Come on Christian, keep going. You can do it. Keep
moving.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
It’s a bit of a squeeze. It’s nicer rock there? Nice. Keep going. You’re doing
really well.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Fantastic work Christian. You’re almost there. Nice work. Keep going. That’s
fantastic. Really good work. Keep going. You’re almost there.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Nice work! Enjoy the view. Really really well done! Right, can one of you check
my knot?
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
What, Christian? No. No, that doesn’t count as a fucking ice cream.
&lt;/p&gt;

        </description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <title>Noughts and Crosses</title>
        <link>https://christianchristiansen.net/log/noughts-and-crosses.html</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jul 2022 17:45:03 AEST</pubDate>
        <guid>
        https://christianchristiansen.net/log/noughts-and-crosses.html
        </guid>
        <description>

&lt;h1 class=&quot;title&quot;&gt;Noughts and Crosses
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;subtitle&quot;&gt;Forging an indefatigable undefeatable foe&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;table-of-contents&quot; role=&quot;doc-toc&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Table of Contents&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;text-table-of-contents&quot; role=&quot;doc-toc&quot;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#setting-the-scene&quot;&gt;Setting the scene&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#the-game&quot;&gt;The game&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#the-programming-language&quot;&gt;The programming language&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#the-program&quot;&gt;The program&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#the-code&quot;&gt;The code&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#start-at-the-beginning&quot;&gt;Start at the beginning&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#data-representation&quot;&gt;Data representation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#icky-inputs-and-outlandish-outputs&quot;&gt;Icky inputs and outlandish outputs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#forging-the-foe&quot;&gt;Forging the foe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#wrap-up&quot;&gt;Wrap up&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#what-next&quot;&gt;What next?&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#play&quot;&gt;Play!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#further-afield&quot;&gt;Further afield&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;outline-container-setting-the-scene&quot; class=&quot;outline-2&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;setting-the-scene&quot;&gt;Setting the scene&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;outline-text-2&quot; id=&quot;text-setting-the-scene&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
By pitting ourselves against opponents and frequently failing, we develop an
understanding of our shortcomings, our prejudices, our inexhaustible capacity
to flop. Games provide safe padded spaces to fall flat on our faces, while
still yielding a sense of accomplishment when we stand firm.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
However, folk are fallible, and friends fickle. To hone our skills at any hour,
against an opponent who will never tire, we have to create a computer ersatz,
an algorithmic adversary, to face our ire. Gather around the kiln, watch and
learn, and see how we forge an indefatigable undefeatable foe from pure
thought-stuff and (metaphorical) fire.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;outline-container-the-game&quot; class=&quot;outline-3&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-game&quot;&gt;The game&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;outline-text-3&quot; id=&quot;text-the-game&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Noughts and crosses, also inexplicably called tic-tac-toe by Yanks, is a game
in which two players alternately place noughts and crosses on a three-by-three
grid; the winner is the first player to place three of their symbol in a
straight line: horizontally, vertically or diagonally.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Consult the relevant Wikipeda article and its citations for more information on
noughts and crosses than you could ever want.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;outline-container-the-programming-language&quot; class=&quot;outline-3&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-programming-language&quot;&gt;The programming language&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;outline-text-3&quot; id=&quot;text-the-programming-language&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Python is the de facto programming language for learning, teaching and
artificial intelligence (amongst many other fields). For the scope of this
tutorial, the use of any other programming language would be a gratuitous
affectation.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The best books on Python are &lt;i&gt;Fluent Python&lt;/i&gt; by Luciano Ramalho and &lt;i&gt;Effective
Python&lt;/i&gt; by Brett Slatkin. For beginners, there are copious stellar resources
available; any search engine is your friend. The Pythonic idioms to be
aware of here, are list comprehension and dunders. More generally, within
this tutorial, the most difficult programming paradigms used are &lt;i&gt;recursion&lt;/i&gt;
and &lt;i&gt;currying&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;The Little Schemer&lt;/i&gt; by Daniel P. Friedman and Matthias
Felleisen is an excellent primer on both of these concepts.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;outline-container-the-program&quot; class=&quot;outline-3&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-program&quot;&gt;The program&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;outline-text-3&quot; id=&quot;text-the-program&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The opponent exhaustively considers every possible move, and determines which
move has the lowest chance of leading to a loss. Many aspects of the program
leave much to be desired. However, the primary purpose of this tutorial is to
demonstrate how to create a simple, non-optimised, artificially intelligent
opponent, and not to win a beauty pageant.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;outline-container-the-code&quot; class=&quot;outline-2&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-code&quot;&gt;The code&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;outline-text-2&quot; id=&quot;text-the-code&quot;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;outline-container-start-at-the-beginning&quot; class=&quot;outline-3&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;start-at-the-beginning&quot;&gt;Start at the beginning&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;outline-text-3&quot; id=&quot;text-start-at-the-beginning&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;org-src-container&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;src src-python&quot;&gt;#!/usr/bin/env python
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;outline-container-data-representation&quot; class=&quot;outline-3&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;data-representation&quot;&gt;Data representation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;outline-text-3&quot; id=&quot;text-data-representation&quot;&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Bad programmers worry about the code. Good programmers worry about data
structures and their relationships.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;quoter&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://lwn.net/Articles/193245/&quot;&gt;Linus Torvalds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
We represent an empty starting board as:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;org-src-container&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;src src-python&quot;&gt;board = &quot; &quot;*9
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
where a space denotes an empty cell, &lt;code&gt;&quot;0&quot;&lt;/code&gt; a nought and &lt;code&gt;&quot;1&quot;&lt;/code&gt; a cross. Players
are represented as &lt;code&gt;False&lt;/code&gt; for noughts and &lt;code&gt;True&lt;/code&gt; for crosses.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
We define which indices represent each row, column and diagonal. Remember that
Python begins indexing at 0, not 1, as Dijkstra ordained.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;org-src-container&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;src src-python&quot;&gt;def rowx(x):
    return [3*x, 3*x+1, 3*x+2]

def coly(y):
    return [0+y, 3+y, 6+y]

diagdown = [0, 4, 8]
diagup = [2, 4, 6]
rows = [rowx(i) for i in range(3)]
cols = [coly(i) for i in range(3)]
diags = [diagdown, diagup]
all_directions = rows + cols + diags
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
To return a list of cells which are still empty:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;org-src-container&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;src src-python&quot;&gt;def possible(board):
    return [i for i, x in enumerate(board) if x == &quot; &quot;]
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
If we insist that noughts always starts first (it is called noughts and crosses
for a reason), we can determine whose turn it is by counting how many cells are
still empty. One great consequence of programming our own game, is being
beholden to our own prejudices and setting our own idiosyncratic rules. &lt;i&gt;Note:&lt;/i&gt;
noughts is denoted by &lt;code&gt;False&lt;/code&gt;, crosses by &lt;code&gt;True&lt;/code&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;org-src-container&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;src src-python&quot;&gt;def player(board):
    return (board.count(&quot; &quot;)-1) % 2
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Knowing the player allows us to figure out what the board looks like after a
move. &lt;i&gt;Note:&lt;/i&gt; &lt;code&gt;int(True) = 1&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;int(False) = 0&lt;/code&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;org-src-container&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;src src-python&quot;&gt;def new_board(board, move):
    return board[:move] + str(int(player(board))) + board[move+1:]
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The following allows us to find out if the game has finished, and if so, who
the winner is:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;org-src-container&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;src src-python&quot;&gt;def moves_left(board):
    return board.count(&quot; &quot;)

def winner(board):
    if moves_left(board) &amp;lt; 5:
        for direction in all_directions:
            try:
                if sum(int(board[i]) for i in direction) == 3:
                    return &quot;X&quot;
                if sum(int(board[i]) for i in direction) == 0:
                    return &quot;O&quot;
            except ValueError:
                continue
        if moves_left(board) == 0:
            return &quot;nobody&quot;
    return False
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;outline-container-icky-inputs-and-outlandish-outputs&quot; class=&quot;outline-3&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;icky-inputs-and-outlandish-outputs&quot;&gt;Icky inputs and outlandish outputs&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;outline-text-3&quot; id=&quot;text-icky-inputs-and-outlandish-outputs&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Humans are visual creatures. Even for geeks with no more than an ASCII console,
a 9 character long string does not suffice as a representation for a board. We
must make at least some minimal pretension to aesthetic nous.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;org-src-container&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;src src-python&quot;&gt;def display_possible(board):
    return &quot;, &quot;.join(str(x) for x in possible(board))

def display_player(p):
    return &quot;X&quot; if p else &quot;O&quot;

def display_cell(x):
    if x == &quot;1&quot;:
        return &quot;X&quot;
    if x == &quot;0&quot;:
        return &quot;O&quot;
    return x

def display(board):
    print()
    print(
        &quot;\n_ _ _\n&quot;.join(
            &quot;|&quot;.join(display_cell(board[3*x+y]) for y in range(3))
            for x in range(3)
        )
    )
    print()
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Humans are not only visual creatures, but also butter-fingered. Use exceptions
to limit the damage a human can do when they mash the keyboard. &lt;code&gt;while True&lt;/code&gt;
loops forever, providing ample time for the not-so-fleet-footed.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;org-src-container&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;src src-python&quot;&gt;def get_human_player():
    while True:
        x = input(&quot;Would you like to be noughts O or crosses X?: &quot;)
        return True if x.lower() == &quot;x&quot; else False

def human_move(board):
    while True:
        try:
            move = input(f&quot;Choose a move from {display_possible(board)}: &quot;)
            if int(move) in possible(board):
                return new_board(board, int(move))
            print(&quot;That number was not valid, please choose another.&quot;)
        except (ValueError, TypeError):
            print(&quot;Please input a number, not a string.&quot;)
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;outline-container-forging-the-foe&quot; class=&quot;outline-3&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;forging-the-foe&quot;&gt;Forging the foe&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;outline-text-3&quot; id=&quot;text-forging-the-foe&quot;&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The enemy of my enemy is my friend.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The algorithm we implement for the computer is called minimax. Namely, the
computer chooses the move which maximises its chances that its opponent will
have minimal chances to win. To calculate the score, minimax recursively calls
itself exhaustively until all potential scenarios have been considered.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;org-src-container&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;src src-python&quot;&gt;def score(result):
    if result == &quot;O&quot;:
        return 1
    if result == &quot;X&quot;:
        return -1
    return 0

def maxmin(x, maximise):
    return max(x) if maximise else min(x)

def minimax(board, maximise=True):
    if result:=winner(board):
        return score(result)
    return maxmin(
        [
            minimax(new_board(board, move), not maximise)
            for move in possible(board)
        ],
        maximise
    )

def computer_best_move(board):
    best_minimax_score = None
    best_move = None
    for move in possible(board):
        minimax_score = minimax(new_board(board, move), maximise=player(board))
        if (
                best_move is None or
                (player(board) and minimax_score &amp;lt; best_minimax_score) or
                (not player(board) and minimax_score &amp;gt; best_minimax_score)
        ):
            best_minimax_score = minimax_score
            best_move = move
    return best_move

def computer_move(board):
    move = computer_best_move(board)
    return new_board(board, move)
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;outline-container-wrap-up&quot; class=&quot;outline-3&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;wrap-up&quot;&gt;Wrap up&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;outline-text-3&quot; id=&quot;text-wrap-up&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
We then put the pieces together to create a playable game. The &lt;code&gt;EOFError&lt;/code&gt; and
&lt;code&gt;KeyboardInterrupt&lt;/code&gt; allow the human player to exit at any time. The dunders
in &lt;code&gt;__name__ == &quot;__main__&quot;&lt;/code&gt; are daft, but alas, all languages have their
defects.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;org-src-container&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;src src-python&quot;&gt;def main(human=False):
    try:
        board = &quot; &quot;*9
        while not winner(board):
            display(board)
            if player(board) == human:
                board = human_move(board)
            else:
                board = computer_move(board)
        display(board)
        print(f&quot;Finished! Winner is {winner(board)}&quot;)
    except (EOFError, KeyboardInterrupt):
        print(&quot;\nAbort\n&quot;)
        exit()

if __name__ == &quot;__main__&quot;:
    HUMAN = get_human_player()
    main(human=HUMAN)
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The complete code is available &lt;a href=&quot;./noughts-and-crosses.py&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;outline-container-what-next&quot; class=&quot;outline-2&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-next&quot;&gt;What next?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;outline-text-2&quot; id=&quot;text-what-next&quot;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;outline-container-play&quot; class=&quot;outline-3&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;play&quot;&gt;Play!&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;outline-text-3&quot; id=&quot;text-play&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Once you have tired of playing against your new-fledged playmate, change it up.
Rewrite the program with other data representations:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class=&quot;org-ol&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;keep track of the moves, not the board;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;rewrite the board as an object;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;use a three-by-three matrix instead of a 9 character long string.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Or improve it! The program could:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class=&quot;org-ol&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;choose better moves (not just the least worst);&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;take symmetry into account, as a three-by-three grid is highly symmetrical;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;use alpha beta pruning;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;have a plusher user interface.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Alternatively, you can translate the program to another programming language.
Or you can create an adversary for another game. Consult your nearest games
cupboard for inspiration.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;outline-container-further-afield&quot; class=&quot;outline-3&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;further-afield&quot;&gt;Further afield&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;outline-text-3&quot; id=&quot;text-further-afield&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
To venture further into the cybernetic meadows, let Richard Brautigan, Andrew
Ng, &lt;i&gt;Deep Learning&lt;/i&gt; by Ian Goodfellow and Yoshua Bengio and Aaron Courville,
and &lt;i&gt;Neural Networks and Learning Machines&lt;/i&gt; by Simon Haykin be your guides.
&lt;i&gt;Bon voyage!&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

        </description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <title>Elvis</title>
        <link>https://christianchristiansen.net/log/elvis.html</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2022 15:23:06 AEST</pubDate>
        <guid>
        https://christianchristiansen.net/log/elvis.html
        </guid>
        <description>

&lt;h1 class=&quot;title&quot;&gt;Elvis&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
‘Come on, choose a song!’
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Four pairs of eyes implore me to pick up the mic. We’re in a dingy room
with a bucket of ice cooling beer bottles set on a low table encircled by a
wrap-around sofa. Three walls need their decor updating; the fourth barely
holds up a beastly screen, blinking at us for input.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
‘All right, all right. Put the cat king on.’
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The four faces turn into question marks.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
‘Elvis Presley,’ I elaborate, switching to English. ‘The cat king!’ I repeat,
switching back to Mandarin.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The four question marks continue to stare at me.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
‘The coolest man ever! The American. The 1950s. &lt;i&gt;Love Me Tender&lt;/i&gt;? &lt;i&gt;Jailhouse
Rock&lt;/i&gt;?’
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
My four companions continue to stare at me. I am being treated to my own
medicine, I think. For the past month, we’ve been roving around bars, electric
with youth, playing dice, eating vodka-drenched watermelon, telling tall tales
over blaring hip-hop, playing pool in smoke-filled backrooms, grimacing over
mahjong tables, cooling off in outdoor swimming pools. And now, we’ve piled
into a kareoke booth giggling, and for the first time, I’m not the clueless
one, asking what the hell is going on.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
‘Let me show you.’
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
猫王 turns up two results. I opt for &lt;i&gt;Blue Suede Shoes&lt;/i&gt;. The poses come out.
The fun kicks in.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
My new friends lean back, swigging on lager, and enjoy the show. Li Ziyi and Li
Zier, sister and brother, share a knowing glance. They had spotted me at
sea in Shenzhen a month ago, and taken an interest in the Chinese-speaking
foreigner. Why had I come? What was I up to? How about we grab a bite? Since
then, we’ve been hanging out every evening and weekend; joined by Jia
Shangshan, the charmer from Shanghai with a permanent cigarette jutting from
the corner of his mouth which wags as he enraptures his latest entourage with
his next fat fib; and Duo Yige, who paired with Li Ziyi, can belt out any
soaring, raucous, Whitney Houston-esque Mandarin ballad. Duo Yige has a
fantastically cheeky grin too. A grin not there when I finish my last Elvis
grunt. They’re all perplexed.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
‘Ah yeah, you see, back then, in the West, cool people were called cats,’ I
explain. ‘And Elvis was the coolest of them all, right? That’s why he’s
called Cat King in Chinese!’ My eyes gleam. It is one of my favourite English
to Chinese name translations.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
My friends disagree. ‘How– just how can a cat be cool?’ asks Li Ziyi.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The notion seems ridiculous. I guess many notions of cool seem ridiculous. I’m
still baffled as to how geil (horny in German) means cool. Lekker (meaning
tasty in most Germanic languages, but also cool in Afrikaans and Dutch) makes
more sense to me. But why then, do Danes and Swedes opt for fed/fett (fat)
instead? And what do Norwegians say? What a mystery.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
‘Cat got your tongue?’ riffs Li Zier.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I open my mouth to try and explain about Squeeze’s &lt;i&gt;Cool for Cats&lt;/i&gt;, about the
cool music video, about how the music video was filmed at John Lennon’s old
house, and how Lennon was cool, and how the Beatles were cool. There’s the
whole Beat generation: &lt;i&gt;On the Road&lt;/i&gt; is chockful of crazy cats and madcats. I
think of Top Cat, with his cool hat. Of course, there’s also Cool Cat, who’s
called Cool Cat. And then there’s Pink Panther, the cat with the coolest theme
tune of them all, on saxophone. That’s cool.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
But then I remember Andrew Lloyd Webber’s &lt;i&gt;Cats&lt;/i&gt;, and close my mouth again,
slinking away.
&lt;/p&gt;

        </description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <title>Edutainment</title>
        <link>https://christianchristiansen.net/log/edutainment.html</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 05 Feb 2022 15:47:55 AEDT</pubDate>
        <guid>
        https://christianchristiansen.net/log/edutainment.html
        </guid>
        <description>

&lt;h1 class=&quot;title&quot;&gt;Edutainment&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
An arrow skewers my foot. A flock follows, darting above our heads, destined
for our flesh, damning us to the ward and worse. I load the rifle and yell out
instructions, and in pain. Those still standing speed through the movements,
with eyes scanning the hills and bushes. But already they’re in our faces.
Bullets wait within barrels as we jab, thrust, parry, pirouette. Blade meets
javelin, dagger splices shield, body hits floor, Death laughs aloud. The
carnage has stopp-. Why? I can’t believe it. It can’t end here. Why does it
always have to crash at this bit? But I won this time!
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I never got &lt;i&gt;Empire Total War&lt;/i&gt; to run on my computer. Every time the first
scene would play out, and regardless of the outcome, a black screen would greet
me. In its stead, &lt;i&gt;Napoleon Total War&lt;/i&gt; taught me about the Egyptian and Italian
campaigns, about Prussia, about howitzers; but I never discovered the
Peninsular Campaign DLC, having eschewed the few video games I played for extra
page-turning.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
My eyes dart across, scanning shelves and titles, searching for a friendly book
amongst the reams of hostile drudgery patiently biding their time to ensnare
another unwitting op-shop-shopper. &lt;i&gt;Death To The French&lt;/i&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;i&gt;Death To The French&lt;/i&gt;? &lt;i&gt;Death To The French&lt;/i&gt;. My fingers cleave the spine out
from the sagging bookcase. 1810. Portugal. C. S. Forester rings a bell. But do
I really want to read a military book, perfumed with English exceptionalism and
mild xenophobia? 1933? Why would anybody have written in 1933 about the
Peninsular War instead of the Great War? What was the Peninsular War anyway? I
buy the book.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Hunger and hunger and hunger pervades the story, incessantly searing through
the plot scorching the characters. The mad, but stoic, Englishman harries the
crazy, and emotional, Frenchmen with help from the sane, but pathetic,
Portuguese guerillas. And they are all starving. Rifleman Dodd, though mad, is
luckily mad for God, King and Country, and therefore prevails. God, King and
Country gift Dodd bread, to munch and munch and munch.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
After shutting the cover, the same questions still confound me. Did I really
want to read a military book, rife with English exceptionalism and mild
xenophobia? 1933? Why would anybody have written in 1933 about the Peninsular
War instead of the Great War? I guess I did find out about the Peninsular War
though.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;b&gt;??????????????&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;b&gt;¿¿¿¿¿¿¿¿¿¿¿¿¿¿̣&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Only philosophers embark on this perilous expedition to the outermost reaches
of language and existence. Some of them fall off, but others cling on
desperately and yell at the people nestling deep in the snug softness, stuffing
themselves with delicious food and drink. ‘Ladies and Gentlemen,’ they yell,
‘we are floating in space!’ But none of the people down there care.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;quoter&quot;&gt;Sophie’s World&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;i&gt;Napoleon Total War&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Death To The French&lt;/i&gt; subtly hoodwinked me
into learning about Prussia and howitzers and starvation by packing in nuggets
of history between fun and guns. &lt;i&gt;Sophie’s World&lt;/i&gt;, on the other hand, is just
one big nugget of history, wearing a fake glasses-nose-moustache combo. Without
any guns.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
With the fake glasses-nose-moustache combo, &lt;i&gt;Sophie’s World&lt;/i&gt; attempts to
disguise itself as a novel, when it is in fact &lt;i&gt;A Fourteen Year Old (Almost
Fifteen Year Old) Schoolchild’s Introduction to (Western) Philosophy&lt;/i&gt;. A plot
is slapped on, with the audience and author standing in for the characters,
Sophie and Alberto, respectively. Indeed, the whole trick of novelisation is
laid bare to the reader, girders and all.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Jostein Gaarder sets out to create a sense of wonder, the wonder of
contemplating the Universe, the wonder of watching a masterful magician change
a couple of white silk scarves into a live rabbit. But Gaarder brings out the
white rabbit onto the stage, coerces it into the top hat with its floppy ears
and chubby cheeks still hanging out, and then proceeds to reveal the
carrot-muncher in the top hat. Ta-da! How’s that for entertainment?
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The textbook is great; the rest, mere bagatelle. But translated into the medium
of a 90s video game, &lt;i&gt;Sophie’s World&lt;/i&gt; is unrecognisable. Ethereal and
ponderous, &lt;i&gt;Sophie’s World&lt;/i&gt; slows down the Universe outside, a force exudes
from it curbing the pace of Nature, warping space, shooing me up a wizard’s
sleeze. Life waits tethered outside as thoughts rocket, dazzle, jab, thrust,
parry, pirouette. Idea meets counterpoint, fun splices ennui, mood hits right,
Absurdists laugh silently. A spirit within promises nirv- No! Why? I can’t
believe it. It can’t end h-
&lt;/p&gt;

        </description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <title>Le Ton beau de Marot</title>
        <link>https://christianchristiansen.net/log/le-ton-beau-de-marot.html</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2022 20:56:29 AEDT</pubDate>
        <guid>
        https://christianchristiansen.net/log/le-ton-beau-de-marot.html
        </guid>
        <description>

&lt;h1 class=&quot;title&quot;&gt;Le Ton beau de Marot&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;verse&quot;&gt;
This poem&lt;br /&gt;
is going&lt;br /&gt;
to devil&lt;br /&gt;
my mettle.&lt;br /&gt;
My mind&#x27;s jammed&lt;br /&gt;
by these damned&lt;br /&gt;
rhymes: A A&lt;br /&gt;
B B… Pray,&lt;br /&gt;
God save me.&lt;br /&gt;
How can three&lt;br /&gt;
miserable&lt;br /&gt;
syllables,&lt;br /&gt;
fourteen pairs,&lt;br /&gt;
wring despairs&lt;br /&gt;
such as these?&lt;br /&gt;
My ill ease&lt;br /&gt;
only grows&lt;br /&gt;
when I pose&lt;br /&gt;
this question:&lt;br /&gt;
‘Translation:&lt;br /&gt;
all in vain?’&lt;br /&gt;
‘No!’ Doug claims,&lt;br /&gt;
as Clément&lt;br /&gt;
retains &lt;i&gt;ton&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
even in&lt;br /&gt;
(though you grin,&lt;br /&gt;
believe him!)&lt;br /&gt;
this poem.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

        </description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <title>Fun</title>
        <link>https://christianchristiansen.net/log/fun.html</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Dec 2021 17:48:00 AEDT</pubDate>
        <guid>
        https://christianchristiansen.net/log/fun.html
        </guid>
        <description>

&lt;h1 class=&quot;title&quot;&gt;Fun&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Seated, I survey the venue from the mezzanine, sipping on 4 dollar lemonade.
Two young girdled men take to the stage; one wields a guitar, the other dabbles
with keys and digital miscellania. With the pulpit still bare, they begin.
Electronic pulses ooze out. The man on the keys, the stouter of the two,
dressed in a white turtleneck and whiter trousers, sings catchy tunes out of
tune.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
There is a fantastic video recording of an early Kraftwerk gig. The audience
for electronic music did not exist yet; so a hodge-podge of subcultures
constitute the punters, hippies arm-in-arm with proto-punks, mullets with
cardigans and eyeliner. When the show started, the packed sedentary curiosity
seekers were clueless of the étiquette for witnessing these new sounds which
heralded the new age. Some meditated; others headbanged, fists included. Yet
more gawped, their gaping mouths preserved for posterity on tape.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
On stage, Barley Passable progress through a kaleidoscope of Euro pop,
electro pop, house, disco — a mélange-mischung of French house and Teutonic
electro — Daft Punk and Berlin nightclubs and too many hours of Eurovision
distilled through teenage Australian ears. “It would be better if they were
German,” opines my partner. I concur. But now, as the crowd swells below, and
the duo start their own Kraftwerk version of the macarena, helped by alcoholic
vapours swirling in the lights, old memories of fun seep through my stupor.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I croak up, free my locks, shift my way down the stairs to join in, and spill
lemonade over my brogues.
&lt;/p&gt;

        </description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <title>We Liars</title>
        <link>https://christianchristiansen.net/log/we-liars.html</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 04 Sep 2021 15:25:37 AEST</pubDate>
        <guid>
        https://christianchristiansen.net/log/we-liars.html
        </guid>
        <description>

&lt;h1 class=&quot;title&quot;&gt;We Liars&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Angus is sitting in the corner, in his wedding dress, playing with three red
juggling balls. He throws them all up at once. Again. And again. He keeps
muttering, ‘this time.’ I watch him with half an eye. After a while, I see he
won’t be achieving whatever it is he has in mind soon, so I don a pair of
headphones and press &lt;i&gt;The Start&lt;/i&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Angus exhales as various electronics begin to purr. He dusts off his wedding
dress and walks towards me, flanked by a choir who yearn for something,
something just out of …
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
A harp twists and the corner falls away, revealing a vast green. Angus invites
me to take his arms as we pass by an array of oblong strings and gusts of
triangles, gurgling mouths without bodies. ‘Where are we going?’ I ask. I’m
too afraid to ask where we are.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Bleeps and bloops jerk my limbs to ecstatic rhythms. Angus towers all six foot
six of himself, wailing, lecturing, howling, over me, and the rest. The
crowd, the mustachioed mass, subsumes me; I osmose myself into this kicking,
dust-purple fantasy.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Three red suns lineate the sky. A ladder stretches asymptotically high. We
climb, struggle together, up, blown by multi-coloured lengths of string
dancing to falsetto honky tonk bitter harmonies emanating from a lounge fan. We
reach the top, we turn our eyes heavenwards, we peer, we see scrawled in pen:
&lt;i&gt;YES&lt;/i&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;

        </description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <title>Зверь</title>
        <link>https://christianchristiansen.net/log/the-beast.html</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 31 May 2021 19:07:46 AEST</pubDate>
        <guid>
        https://christianchristiansen.net/log/the-beast.html
        </guid>
        <description>

&lt;h1 class=&quot;title&quot;&gt;Зверь&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;org47bd748&quot; class=&quot;figure&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;./the-beast.webp&quot; alt=&quot;the-beast.webp&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
What is there to do in Duisburg? To start with, perhaps a saunter around the
world&#x27;s largest inland harbour? Restaurants hug its banks, keen for a view of
the concrete basin. Further to the city centre, kebab stalls line
the pathways. There&#x27;s even a theater where the latest misguided, desperate and
lost troupe find themselves performing to the vestiges of a decaying
post-industrial city.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
My mother opts to take me and my brother to the library, undoubtedly due to
the lack of internet access in our newly rented accommodation. As the weeks
tick by, we are still waiting for a professional to rock up with a router,
plug it into the tangle of the Internet and chant a few choice incantations
to bless our bare abode with megabits and millisecond pings. My mother&#x27;s unable
to wait for the famed efficiency of Teutonic bureaucracy: she has electronic
mail to read.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Scowering past the rows of shelves brimming with Goethe, Mann, Schiller and
odd spines with spiky Fraktur characters, I search for reading more suited to
my ability. My pathetic attempt a few days ago to ask where swimwear and
goggles could be bought at our new local swimming pool, blatantly
demonstrated that three years of German lessons in England had not amounted to
much.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I spy some teenage fiction I&#x27;ve read before. Alex Rider, perfect! Knowing the
characters, premise and plot should make reading in a new language a less
foreboding task. Alas, the first few words of German already muddle my mind.
But then, I finally stumble upon the jackpot.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Garfield.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Full of indispensable vocabulary, such as &quot;Pastaspäher&quot;, &quot;Lasagne&quot; and &quot;Nein&quot;,
Garfield quickly equips me with the essentials needed to navigate these new
environs.
&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div id=&quot;orgeef51a8&quot; class=&quot;figure&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;./the-beast-2.webp&quot; alt=&quot;the-beast-2.webp&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I&#x27;m free this weekend. Typing &lt;code&gt;Events in Sydney&lt;/code&gt; into my web browser reveals a
Japanese film festival at the Art Gallery of New South Wales. Skimming through
the blurbs, the phrase &quot;experimental horror&quot; pops out. I know exactly who
will join me for this.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;i&gt;House&lt;/i&gt; is a fusillade on the brain cells and a smorgasbord of filmic
delights&amp;#x2026; Described as ‘unhinged extreme’, &lt;i&gt;House&lt;/i&gt; (aka &lt;i&gt;Hausu&lt;/i&gt;) is an
experimental horror film that amalgamates 1970s pop culture with mysterious
phenomenology.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
We arrive, settle in, and a white cat appears.
&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div id=&quot;org5093cbf&quot; class=&quot;figure&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;./russian-course.webp&quot;
alt=&quot;russian-course.webp&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Packing for a weekend is an art I have perfected. My backpack fits a rolled-up
shirt, a couple of changes of underwear, a book, an apple or two and a water
bottle. My jacket, coat, sweater and trousers can easily last a weekend, even
with long-haul bus trips. A toothbrush and perhaps a perfume bottle can be
stowed away into one of the side pockets; everything else can be borrowed when
I reach my destination. Oslo, Copenhagen, London, Amsterdam, Berlin, Geneva,
Madrid, each weekend there&#x27;s another friend to visit, another festival to
attend, another chance to snatch a moment together with my partner, to remove
the telephone which separates our voices, to feel her breath on my skin, to
violate the definition of &quot;long-distance relationship&quot; for a few glorious days.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Packing for life with my partner on a new continent has me stumped. What parts
of myself do I want to keep? Which clothes, hobbies, memories, dreams,
affectations will match our new surroundings?
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
We&#x27;ve already decided on bringing a musical instrument each, which leaves one
suitcase and one piece of hand luggage. Crockery, cutlery, clothes will be easy
to find in charity shops once we&#x27;re in Sydney. Books too, and if not then
surely at a library. As I stack my books onto bookshelves and unpack and pack
them from storage boxes, I pick up a battered textbook, &lt;i&gt;The New Penguin
Russian Course&lt;/i&gt;. The receipt remains inside, the date marks the length of time
I have failed to realise a naïve teenage dream to learn Russian. A certain
stubbornness washes over me and I resolve to finish what I started eight years
ago. I place the book in my carry-on pile.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Two flights later, and many more reading hours, I reach the end of Nicholas
Brown&#x27;s text. What&#x27;s next? I&#x27;m not sure if Garfield has been translated into
Russian, but surely the Harry Potters have. Indeed, I spot a couple of the
later books at Abbey&#x27;s Bookshop, but there&#x27;s no Philosopher&#x27;s Stone&amp;#x2026; I order
a copy at the counter and pick up &lt;i&gt;New Penguin Parallel Text Short Stories in
Russian&lt;/i&gt; to tide me over.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
As I leaf through, a дедушка consoles me, before arms reach out from the pages
and grasp onto me, arms of widows selling the remains of their war-hero
husbands, an arm tattooed on the sea, the still shaking arms of a priest
executioner.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Once in, I see him. He is waiting for me as if it were time to introduce
himself. He is sitting in the armchair - a huge, confident cat - with his
chubby cheeks turned toward me.
&lt;/p&gt;

        </description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <title>Develop a Hello World alert for Windows on Arch Linux</title>
        <link>https://christianchristiansen.net/log/windows.html</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 12:57:24 AEDT</pubDate>
        <guid>
        https://christianchristiansen.net/log/windows.html
        </guid>
        <description>

&lt;h1 class=&quot;title&quot;&gt;Develop a Hello World alert for Windows on Arch Linux&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Only proceed when all possibilities to avoid Windows have dried up.
Proceed with care and suspicion: Clippy takes no prisoners.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;outline-container-org6d9cd8b&quot; class=&quot;outline-2&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;org6d9cd8b&quot;&gt;Step 1: Hello World&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;outline-text-2&quot; id=&quot;text-org6d9cd8b&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Write the program.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;code&gt;helloword.cpp&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;org-src-container&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;src src-C++&quot;&gt;#ifndef UNICODE // Not strictly necessary, but good practice
#define UNICODE
#endif

#include &amp;lt;windows.h&amp;gt; // Use Windows libraries

int WINAPI wWinMain(
    HINSTANCE hInstance,     // Handle to current instance
    HINSTANCE hPrevInstance, // Handle to previous instance of application
    PWSTR pCmdLine,          // Command line arguments as Unicode string
    int nCmdShow)            // Open minimised, maximised, or normally
{
    MessageBox (
        NULL,            // Handle to owner of the message box
        L&quot;Hello world!&quot;, // Message to be displayed
        L&quot;Hello&quot;,        // Pop-up title
        MB_OKCANCEL);    // Contents and behaviour of pop-up
    return 0;
}
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Further documentation on &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/windows/win32/learnwin32/winmain--the-application-entry-point&quot;&gt;wWinMain&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/windows/win32/api/winuser/nf-winuser-messagebox&quot;&gt;MessageBox&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;outline-container-org024b75b&quot; class=&quot;outline-2&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;org024b75b&quot;&gt;Step 2: GNU Compiler Collection&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;outline-text-2&quot; id=&quot;text-org024b75b&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Compile the program.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Running &lt;code&gt;gcc&lt;/code&gt; without any modifications will not work, as we require
supplementary Windows libraries.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;org-src-container&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;src src-sh&quot;&gt;sudo pacman -S mingw-w64-headers mingw-w64-cpp
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Then if we run
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;org-src-container&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;src src-sh&quot;&gt;x86_64-w64-mingw32-g++ helloworld.cpp
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
we will get an &lt;a href=&quot;https://stackoverflow.com/questions/58324230/undefined-reference-to-winmain-c-mingw&quot;&gt;error&lt;/a&gt; about an &lt;code&gt;undefined reference to `WinMain&#x27;&lt;/code&gt; . What we&#x27;re
missing is the flag &lt;code&gt;-municode&lt;/code&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;org-src-container&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;src src-sh&quot;&gt;x86_64-w64-mingw32-g++ -municode helloworld.cpp
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Out pops &lt;code&gt;a.exe&lt;/code&gt;. We have now created our first Windows program on Arch Linux!
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;outline-container-orgdab56e0&quot; class=&quot;outline-2&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;orgdab56e0&quot;&gt;Step 3: Wine&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;outline-text-2&quot; id=&quot;text-orgdab56e0&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Run the program.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.winehq.org&quot;&gt;Wine&lt;/a&gt; allows us to run Windows programs on Linux. To install Wine on Arch Linux,
we will first have to enable the &lt;code&gt;multilib&lt;/code&gt; repository by uncommenting two
lines in &lt;code&gt;/etc/pacman.conf&lt;/code&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;code&gt;/etc/pacman.conf&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;org-src-container&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;src src-sh&quot;&gt;# [multilib]
# Include = /etc/pacman.d/mirrorlist
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Then update the repositories, and install the following packages:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;org-src-container&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;src src-sh&quot;&gt;sudo pacman -Syu
sudo pacman -S wine wine-mono
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Run
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;org-src-container&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;src src-sh&quot;&gt;wine a.exe
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
and bask in triumph.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;./windows.webp&quot; alt=&quot;windows.webp&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;outline-container-orge162603&quot; class=&quot;outline-2&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;orge162603&quot;&gt;Further steps&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;outline-text-2&quot; id=&quot;text-orge162603&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Write more programs.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Try following &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/windows/win32/learnwin32/your-first-windows-program&quot;&gt;tutorials&lt;/a&gt; on creating more involved Windows programs.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

        </description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <title>Escape Meta Alt Control Shift</title>
        <link>https://christianchristiansen.net/log/escape-meta-alt-control-shift.html</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 20 Mar 2021 16:56:22 AEDT</pubDate>
        <guid>
        https://christianchristiansen.net/log/escape-meta-alt-control-shift.html
        </guid>
        <description>

&lt;h1 class=&quot;title&quot;&gt;Escape Meta Alt Control Shift&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;figure&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;./pinky.webp&quot; alt=&quot;pinky.webp&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Rock climbing, guitar playing, ivory tickling, and GNU Emacs have all become
inextricable parts of my life. And all of them demand far too much of my left
pinky. After slightly straining my left wrist on a crimpy dynamic slab, I have
become acutely aware of the punishing ritual I subject my weakest finger to
from dawn till dusk.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://ergoemacs.org/emacs/emacs_pinky.html&quot;&gt;Emacs pinky&lt;/a&gt; is an undeniable issue amongst programmers. I already alleviate
stress by using &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.emacswiki.org/emacs/Evil&quot;&gt;evil-mode&lt;/a&gt;, remapping &lt;code&gt;Caps Lock&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;Escape&lt;/code&gt;, and raising my
wrists above the keyboard by shoving a sweater underneath my arms. However, I
still expect my left pinky to auto-complete with &lt;code&gt;Tab&lt;/code&gt;, return to command mode
with &lt;code&gt;Caps Lock&lt;/code&gt; (masquerading as &lt;code&gt;Escape&lt;/code&gt;), capitalise letters with &lt;code&gt;Shift&lt;/code&gt;,
change buffers (and run countless other Emacs commands) with &lt;code&gt;Control&lt;/code&gt;, switch
windows via &lt;a href=&quot;https://swaywm.org&quot;&gt;sway&lt;/a&gt; with &lt;code&gt;Super&lt;/code&gt; (aka &lt;code&gt;Meta&lt;/code&gt; or the Windows key), and, of course,
press &lt;code&gt;Alt&lt;/code&gt; to help summon the genie &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;M-x&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I should surely be able to find some method to further reduce my poor digit&#x27;s
burden.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;outline-container-orgd25080a&quot; class=&quot;outline-2&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;orgd25080a&quot;&gt;Space as a leading key?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;outline-text-2&quot; id=&quot;text-orgd25080a&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Doom Emacs and Spacemacs eschew &lt;code&gt;Control&lt;/code&gt; in favour of &lt;code&gt;Space&lt;/code&gt; for commands.
The briefest of flirtations with Doom has convinced me for life that there is
nothing as perverse as using another human&#x27;s Emacs config. Afer restoring my
&lt;code&gt;~/.emacs.d/&lt;/code&gt; and sanity, I found no easy way to extricate the leading space
behaviour from either Doom and Spacemacs.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I delved further into abandoned forums to seek a more viable (and less deviant)
option.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;outline-container-orgc47425e&quot; class=&quot;outline-2&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;orgc47425e&quot;&gt;Caps as Escape and Control?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;outline-text-2&quot; id=&quot;text-orgc47425e&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://gitlab.com/interception/linux/plugins/caps2esc&quot;&gt;caps2esc&lt;/a&gt; showed promise. It remaps not only &lt;code&gt;Caps Lock&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;Escape&lt;/code&gt;, but also
allows &lt;code&gt;Caps Lock&lt;/code&gt; to act as &lt;code&gt;Control&lt;/code&gt; whilst it is held down. &lt;a href=&quot;https://gitlab.com/interception/linux/plugins/space2meta/&quot;&gt;space2meta&lt;/a&gt;
remaps &lt;code&gt;Space&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;Meta&lt;/code&gt; (aka &lt;code&gt;Super&lt;/code&gt;) whilst it is held down. And both run on
the &lt;code&gt;udev&lt;/code&gt; level so they are window manager agnostic and work in TTY!
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I started copy-pasting code and creating my own &lt;code&gt;caps2meta&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;return2meta&lt;/code&gt;, and
&lt;code&gt;space2ctrl&lt;/code&gt;, until I thought there must be an even better solution.
And, indeed, there is.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;outline-container-orgc620fc9&quot; class=&quot;outline-2&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;orgc620fc9&quot;&gt;Dual Function Keys&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;outline-text-2&quot; id=&quot;text-orgc620fc9&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://gitlab.com/interception/linux/plugins/dual-function-keys&quot;&gt;Dual Function Keys&lt;/a&gt; allows anybody to remap any key to any other key when it is
tapped, double-tapped or held down.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
To install on Arch Linux, simply:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;org-src-container&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;src src-sh&quot;&gt;sudo pacman -S interception-dual-function-keys
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Then create a YAML file describing the key remappings required. In my personal
config: &lt;code&gt;Caps Lock&lt;/code&gt; becomes &lt;code&gt;Escape&lt;/code&gt; when tapped, and &lt;code&gt;Meta&lt;/code&gt; / &lt;code&gt;Super&lt;/code&gt; when
held; &lt;code&gt;Space&lt;/code&gt; becomes &lt;code&gt;Ctrl&lt;/code&gt; when held; &lt;code&gt;Enter&lt;/code&gt; / &lt;code&gt;Return&lt;/code&gt; becomes &lt;code&gt;Meta&lt;/code&gt; /
&lt;code&gt;Super&lt;/code&gt; when held.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;code&gt;~/.config/dfk.yaml&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;org-src-container&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;src src-yaml&quot;&gt;TIMING:
    TAP_MILLISEC: 200
    DOUBLE_TAP_MILLISEC: 150

MAPPINGS:
    - KEY: KEY_CAPSLOCK
      TAP: KEY_ESC
      HOLD: KEY_LEFTMETA

    - KEY: KEY_SPACE
      TAP: KEY_SPACE
      HOLD: KEY_LEFTCTRL

    - KEY: KEY_ENTER
      TAP: KEY_ENTER
      HOLD: KEY_LEFTMETA
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Create a YAML file in &lt;code&gt;/etc/interception/udevmon.d/&lt;/code&gt; for the system
configuration.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;code&gt;/etc/interception/udevmon.d/keys.yaml&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;org-src-container&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;src src-yaml&quot;&gt;- JOB: intercept -g $DEVNODE | dual-function-keys -c /path/to/dfk.yaml | uinput -d $DEVNODE
  DEVICE:
    EVENTS:
      EV_KEY: [KEY_CAPSLOCK, KEY_SPACE, KEY_ENTER]
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Now to get the keybindings up and running:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;org-src-container&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;src src-sh&quot;&gt;sudo udevmon
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
To have the keybindings start automatically at boot-time:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;org-src-container&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;src src-sh&quot;&gt;sudo systemctl enable udevmon
sudo systemctl start udevmon
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;outline-container-org0bf2b04&quot; class=&quot;outline-2&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;org0bf2b04&quot;&gt;Addendum&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;outline-text-2&quot; id=&quot;text-org0bf2b04&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Et voilà! My thumb and right pinky can now relieve my left pinky of most of its
duties. And I&#x27;ll soon be back on the wall, cursing crimpy dynamic slabs.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

        </description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <title>FBi Radio currently playing. Christian Christiansen.</title>
        <link>https://christianchristiansen.net/log/fbiradio.html</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2021 19:00:00 AEDT</pubDate>
        <guid>
        https://christianchristiansen.net/log/fbiradio.html
        </guid>
        <description>

&lt;h1 class=&quot;title&quot;&gt;FBi Radio currently playing&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;figure&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;./fbiradio.webp&quot; alt=&quot;fbiradio.webp&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Amongst all the wild and fantastical affairs humans partake in, music is by far
the most baffling. We indoctrinate our infants with lullabies, make pilgrimages
to clubs, festivals and operas, and buy our groceries whilst barely pubescent
teenagers serenade us over tinny tannoys. There are no clear evolutionary
advantages associated with an appreciation of Bach&#x27;s fugues or gabber; music is
an inexplicable and joyous byproduct of the human condition.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Since arriving in Australia, &lt;a href=&quot;https://fbiradio.com&quot;&gt;FBi Radio&lt;/a&gt;, the independent non-profit radio station
which plays 50% Australian music (of which 50% is from New South Wales), has
satiated my desire for novel tracks and artists, and helped me to delve into the
local culture and survive a year without the euphoria of dancing with a
hundred fellow revelers. Tkay Maidza, 3NDLES5, Crazymike, Shady Nasty, Low
Flung, Party Dozen, Cool Sounds, &amp;#x2026; (the list is far too long to properly
compile) - they all immeasurably improved my year.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
With so many great artists and tracks on FBi, I&#x27;ve struggled with having to
visit the website, find the current program, and scroll to locate what&#x27;s
currently playing everytime my ears are piqued. To solve this, I have created a
&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/cchristiansen/fbiradio/&quot;&gt;Python script&lt;/a&gt;. Now I just have to type &lt;code&gt;fbiplaying&lt;/code&gt; and the answer falls right
into my lap. Now excuse me - I need to check out what the current track is.
It&#x27;s wild.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Listen to 94.5 FM.
&lt;/p&gt;

        </description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <title>La Fille aux yeux d'or. Christian Christiansen.</title>
        <link>https://christianchristiansen.net/log/girl-with-the-golden-eyes.html</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2020 12:00:00 AEST</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">
        https://christianchristiansen.net/log/girl-with-the-golden-eyes.html
        </guid>
        <description> Writing on Balzac's novella, to be found &lt;a
        href=&quot;https://christianchristiansen.net/log/girl-with-the-golden-eyes.html&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.
        </description>
        <guid>
        https://christianchristiansen.net/log/girl-with-the-golden-eyes.html
        </guid>
        <description>


&lt;center&gt;&lt;h1&gt;La Fille aux yeux d&#x27;or&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;../portfolio/la-fille-painting.webp&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The lights go back on. The punters shield their eyes, wipe sweat off their
foreheads, trickle out, past the cloakroom onto Oxford Street, lighting up,
with grins larger than faces.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Tuesday 2&lt;sup style=&quot;font-size: 14px;&quot;&gt;nd&lt;/sup&gt; December 2014, at the 100 Club,
London. Iceage have just completed a seering set, whilst touring off the back
of their third album.  &lt;cite&gt;Plowing Into the Field of Love&lt;/cite&gt; saw the
Danish punk band expand, explore, embrace a greater lyrical and musical
landscape, delving into instrumentation and lyrical themes only hinted at in
the nihilistic &lt;cite&gt;You&#x27;re Nothing&lt;/cite&gt;, whilst retaining their sharpness,
their danger.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;q&gt;The only current punk band I can think of that sounds really dangerous.&lt;/q&gt;
- Iggy Pop. Danger evident throughout today&#x27;s gig. The gaggle who had turned
out this evening were hard to discern, Nick Cave fans, posers, remnants from past
tours, and those who simply wanted to steal a glance of the handsome quartet.
But from the first twang of guitar, it was evident who the bulk of the audience
were. They shoved, dived, shouted back lyrics, with raised fists. They were
here to see the best punk band in punk&#x27;s own city. And they have. On their way
out, palpable satisfaction hangs in the sweaty air.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The unmistakable hiss of an amp comes back on. Confusion erupts.
&quot;Iceage don&#x27;t do encores?!&quot; But the foursome are back on, and we pile back
in. I reach the front, crash onto the stage, thrust by the mob behind. I lie
there, staring up, watching from below Elias Rønnenfelt bewitch the ruckus
abound. Watching our generation&#x27;s Elvis, our Bob Dylan, our Ian Curtis.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;line-height: 1;&quot;&gt;Raise your fists
For the depraved roses
Raise it today
Everything drifts
Soon it&#x27;s gone
Don&#x27;t find a place to stay&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;img style=&quot;width: 105px; height: 60px;&quot; src=&quot;iceage-logos.webp&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Today, five years on, I am listening to the crooners from the antipodes. The
gang of four have swelled and gained a guitarist, and a maraca shaker. The
fury of the mosh pit is replaced with luxurious lounge listening.
Cowboy tassels, snakeskin boots, 1000-mile
stares are being filmed live by a camera crew courtesy of Brodie Sessions, as
Iceage saunter through songs inspired by Mina, Pieter Bruegel the Elder, and
Samuel Beckett. The spectacle finishes with a rendition of &lt;cite&gt;Lockdown
Blues&lt;/cite&gt;, their latest covid-19 inspired single.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Incontent with simply providing a new single, a wondrous livestreamed show, and
a vast backlog of influences to uncover, Iceage have also contributed a list of
suggested books for reading over this pandemic period:
&lt;cite&gt;The Bluest Eye&lt;/cite&gt; by Toni Morrison, &lt;cite&gt;Papillon&lt;/cite&gt; by
Henry Charrière, &lt;cite&gt;The Happy Birthday of Death&lt;/cite&gt; by Gregory Corso,
&lt;cite&gt;God&#x27;s Mistress&lt;/cite&gt; by James Galvin, and &lt;cite&gt;The Girl with the
Golden Eyes&lt;/cite&gt; by Honoré de Balzac.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;the-girl-with-the-golden-eyes.webp&quot;&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I ordered a copy of &lt;cite&gt;The Girl with the Golden Eyes&lt;/cite&gt;; the book&#x27;s
cover posed even more questions than the title (never mind the blurb:
&lt;q&gt; The greatest French novelist of all time tells the story of a man enslaved
by a strange girl who bewitched him, ignited his passion, taught him all the
ways of love and then revealed herself as captive to the most grotesque
perversion known to human flesh&lt;/q&gt;). Count me in.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Chapter 1, even in translation, unveiled a new realm of linguistic
possibilities to me; Balzac&#x27;s descriptions of Parisian society uprooted my
notions of what language is capable of expressing.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;line-height: 1; &quot;&gt;
Thus we are brought to the third circle of this hell, which, perhaps, will some
day find its Dante. In this third social circle, a sort of Parisian belly, in
which the interest of the town are digested, and where they are condensed into
the form known as &lt;i&gt;business&lt;/i&gt;, there moves and agitates, as by some acrid
and bitter intestinal process, the crowd of lawyers, doctors, notaries,
councillors, business men, bankers, big merchants, speculators and magistrates.
Here are to be found even more causes of moral and physical destruction than
elsewhere. These people - almost all of them - live in unhealthy offices, in
fetid ante-chambers, in little barred dens, and spend their days bowed down
beneath the weight of affairs; they rise at dawn to be in time, not to be left
behind, to gain all or not to lose, to over-reach a man or his money, to open or
wind up some business, to take advantage of some fleeting opportunity, to get a
man hanged or set him free. They infect their horses, they over-drive and age
and break them, like their own legs, before their time. Time is their tyrant: it
fails them, it escapes them; they can neither expand it nor cut it short. What
soul can remain great, pure, moral and generous, and, consequently, what face
retain its beauty in this depraving practice of a calling which compels one to
bear the weight of the public sorrows, to analyse them, to weight them,
estimate them, and mark them out by rule? Where do these folk put aside their
hearts?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
It is a shame that chapter 2 goes on to explore the limits of story telling
with wafer-thin characterisation, an incredulous plot, wanton literary and
cultural references, and scarcely discernible narration. And an abrupt ending.
&lt;/p&gt;


        </description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <title>First commit to KDE. Christian Christiansen.</title>
        <link>https://christianchristiansen.net/log/kde-first-commit.html</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 11 Apr 2020 12:00:00 AEST</pubDate>
        <guid>
        https://christianchristiansen.net/log/kde-first-commit.html
        </guid>
        <description>


&lt;center&gt;&lt;h1&gt;First commit to KDE&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After years of reading Linux Format, then Linux Voice, now finding refuge
in &lt;a href=&quot;https://latenightlinux.com/&quot;&gt;Late Night Linux&lt;/a&gt;; after scouring
through countless forums over a decade ago to ornate my desktop with ever
fancier bling (and wobblier windows); after wrecking multiple installations
from ever more ridiculous projects (who knew that running state-of-the-art
games through Wine on a tiny Sony Vaio laptop without a GPU wasn&#x27;t a sensible
idea?), I have finally contributed back to the open source community.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I stumbled across a recommendation to read the excellent
&lt;a href=&quot;https://producingoss.com&quot;&gt;Producing Open Source Software&lt;/a&gt; by Karl
Fogel.
The book demystified the inner workings of open source, and had me itching to
join in. So I set about on a mission to do so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Step 1: Hang out on IRC.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See what&#x27;s happening.
To be honest, I couldn&#x27;t see much happening on IRC, but I quickly became
frustrated by Konversation&#x27;s inability to log my nickname in automatically.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Step 2: Find out what the issue was.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apparently NickServ is no
longer the go-to identification service and I should have been using SASL
instead. &lt;a href=&quot;https://bugs.kde.org/show_bug.cgi?id=400362&quot;&gt;Why wasn&#x27;t that
the default?&lt;/a&gt; Nobody was able to say - everybody seemed to think it was a
sensible idea. Time to get stuck in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Step 3: Get the build environment running.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was a real pain, despite KDE&#x27;s
&lt;a href=&quot;https://community.kde.org/Get_Involved/development&quot;&gt;impeccable wiki
&lt;/a&gt; to help get started. Although LTS releases are
incredibly useful for a multitude of reasons, I found out the hard way
that they&#x27;re ill-suited for development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Step 4: Change the code.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And test, test, test. Diving into new territory always contains several
unforeseen pitfalls. However, I soon had something working, and sent it off
to review. Again, KDE has
&lt;a href=&quot;https://community.kde.org/Infrastructure/Phabricator&quot;&gt;excellent
documentation&lt;/a&gt; for newcomers. After a minor edit...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Step 5: Celebrate.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It got accepted! Woohoo! Champagne for everyone¹!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ah wait, somebody on the #konversation channel has found another annoying
bug... Hold my flute.&lt;/p&gt;


        </description>
    </item>
</channel>
</rss>
